<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Brian Perry]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thoughts about web development and occasionally Nintendo.]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:54:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Learning How to Adapt - Developing Up]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Enjoyed listening back to this chat about adapting as a developer that I had with <a href="https://twitter.com/mikemiles86">Mike Miles</a> for his <a href="http://www.developingup.com/">Developing Up podcast</a>. We end up pretty far away from some of the traditional dev topics you might expect, but I think that is the improviser in me applying  'yes, and...' to our conversation. Mike does a great job reinforcing how some of my more tangential thoughts relate back to adaptability. Not to mention some great editing - you can hardly tell that we were talking at the end of a long day at a conference.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/learning-how-to-adapt-developing-up/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/learning-how-to-adapt-developing-up/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Enjoyed listening back to this chat about adapting as a developer that I had with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikemiles86&quot;&gt;Mike Miles&lt;/a&gt; for his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.developingup.com/&quot;&gt;Developing Up podcast&lt;/a&gt;. We end up pretty far away from some of the traditional dev topics you might expect, but I think that is the improviser in me applying  &apos;yes, and...&apos; to our conversation. Mike does a great job reinforcing how some of my more tangential thoughts relate back to adaptability. Not to mention some great editing - you can hardly tell that we were talking at the end of a long day at a conference.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In The Garage: Joyce Manor Share The Scenes And Stories Behind Million Dollars To Kill Me]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>This January, they’re co-headlining the 3,700-cap Hollywood Palladium with Jeff Rosenstock, who they consider a fellow “last man standing” in their scene and the man responsible for Joyce Manor’s first paid gig in 2010. “As we were leaving, he asked ‘You guys get paid?'” Johnson recalls. “We’re like, it’s cool, we’re from around here, it’s fine. And he’s like no, no, no,” handing the band $100 out of his pocket.</blockquote>
<p>Great profile in general, but this moment between two of my favorite bands stuck with me. Amazing to see Rosenstock give them what I'd imagine to be a non-trivial amount of money at the time just because he feels strongly that people should be compensated for their work. And I love that this impulsive moment also sticks with Joyce Manor eight years later as co-headliners. While I've never just handed someone $100, I can only hope that back in my improv days or now in the open source community I've had some small moments that have stuck with folks.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/in-the-garage:-joyce-manor-share-the-scenes-and-stories-behind-million-dollars-to-kill-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/in-the-garage:-joyce-manor-share-the-scenes-and-stories-behind-million-dollars-to-kill-me/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;This January, they’re co-headlining the 3,700-cap Hollywood Palladium with Jeff Rosenstock, who they consider a fellow “last man standing” in their scene and the man responsible for Joyce Manor’s first paid gig in 2010. “As we were leaving, he asked ‘You guys get paid?&apos;” Johnson recalls. “We’re like, it’s cool, we’re from around here, it’s fine. And he’s like no, no, no,” handing the band $100 out of his pocket.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great profile in general, but this moment between two of my favorite bands stuck with me. Amazing to see Rosenstock give them what I&apos;d imagine to be a non-trivial amount of money at the time just because he feels strongly that people should be compensated for their work. And I love that this impulsive moment also sticks with Joyce Manor eight years later as co-headliners. While I&apos;ve never just handed someone $100, I can only hope that back in my improv days or now in the open source community I&apos;ve had some small moments that have stuck with folks.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beach]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Current status: enjoying the beach.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/beach/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/beach/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Current status: enjoying the beach.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Design Tool Dilemma - freeCodeCamp]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Found this article especially relevant as I'm currently following just behind our UX team prototyping in code as they design early mockups using InVision. The spirit of what we're doing is aiming for the "collaborative" narrative outlined in this post, but the fact that there is still a handoff occasionally makes it feel like what the article calls “bridging the gap.” It is very early days, but I'm anxious for a future where more of our tools can speak the same language and actually impact code that will be used in the final project. Still a long way to go on that front though.</p>
<p>I found this embedded quote to be especially insightful:</p>
<blockquote>
Production code is a surrogate for decision-making power. Production code is the source of truth. It is the realtime sum total of all the conversations, all the decisions, all the politics…it is everything. Whoever is pushing code to production is running the product. Everyone else only has influence.
<cite><a href="http://www.artypapers.com/ap.log/thread.php?346">Rebekah Cox</a></cite>
 </blockquote>
<p>I don't necessarily want all of that power. In a perfect world, I help enable others to assert control on the areas of the project where they are experts. With our current tools there is just too much risk of things being lost in translation. Today we're doing the best we can with the tools we have and against all odds we often find a way to make it work.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/the-design-tool-dilemma-freecodecamp/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/the-design-tool-dilemma-freecodecamp/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Found this article especially relevant as I&apos;m currently following just behind our UX team prototyping in code as they design early mockups using InVision. The spirit of what we&apos;re doing is aiming for the &quot;collaborative&quot; narrative outlined in this post, but the fact that there is still a handoff occasionally makes it feel like what the article calls “bridging the gap.” It is very early days, but I&apos;m anxious for a future where more of our tools can speak the same language and actually impact code that will be used in the final project. Still a long way to go on that front though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found this embedded quote to be especially insightful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Production code is a surrogate for decision-making power. Production code is the source of truth. It is the realtime sum total of all the conversations, all the decisions, all the politics…it is everything. Whoever is pushing code to production is running the product. Everyone else only has influence.
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artypapers.com/ap.log/thread.php?346&quot;&gt;Rebekah Cox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
 &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t necessarily want all of that power. In a perfect world, I help enable others to assert control on the areas of the project where they are experts. With our current tools there is just too much risk of things being lost in translation. Today we&apos;re doing the best we can with the tools we have and against all odds we often find a way to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How Did This Get Made - Rad Live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Back in June I got a chance to see a taping of <a href="https://www.hdtgminfo.com/">How Did This Get Made</a>, which is one of my all time favorite podcasts. I was coming home from Texas that day and just barely made it to the show in time because my flight was delayed. Thankfully all of the travel stress was worth it - seeing the show live was amazing, and our 80's BMX Bike movie <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091817/">Rad</a> was the best kind of bad movie.</p>
<p>They released <a href="https://www.earwolf.com/episode/rad-live/">the live show as a podcast episode</a> a few weeks back, and it is well worth the listen.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/how-did-this-get-made-rad-live/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/how-did-this-get-made-rad-live/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Back in June I got a chance to see a taping of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdtgminfo.com/&quot;&gt;How Did This Get Made&lt;/a&gt;, which is one of my all time favorite podcasts. I was coming home from Texas that day and just barely made it to the show in time because my flight was delayed. Thankfully all of the travel stress was worth it - seeing the show live was amazing, and our 80&apos;s BMX Bike movie &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091817/&quot;&gt;Rad&lt;/a&gt; was the best kind of bad movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.earwolf.com/episode/rad-live/&quot;&gt;the live show as a podcast episode&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks back, and it is well worth the listen.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Frank Turner Be More Kind Tour]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In June I had the chance to see two dates of the Be More Kind tour with Frank Turner and the Sleeping Souls. Both shows had completely different and amazing sets of openers.</p>
<p>June 23, 2018 - Aragon Ballroom (Chicago)</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://themenzingers.com/">The Menzingers</a> - Happy to finally get a chance to see these guys live after listening to them since Chamberlain Waits. Had the whole place singing along, even as openers.</li>
<li><a href="http://luceromusic.com/">Lucero</a> - I've seen Lucero before, so I knew they put on a great show and have been on the road long enough to have zero fucks left to give. Even knowing that, I was shocked that they came out and played their entire unreleased new album front to back. The new album sounds great, but would have been nice to hear a song or two I knew.</li>
<li><a href="http://frank-turner.com/">Frank Turner and the Sleeping Souls</a> - a surprisingly well oiled machine live. The stuff off of his new album Be More Kind sounded great live.</li>
</ul> 
 <p>June 27, 2018 - Royale (Boston)</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://restorations.bandcamp.com/">Restorations</a> - Double dipped on this tour via stubhub for a chance to see this band, and they put on a fantastic opening set. Can't recommend them enough.</li>
<li><a href="https://jeffrosenstock.bandcamp.com/">Jeff Rosenstock</a> - since this was a one off gig he played the set acoustic (a little over half solo, the rest with some local friends backing him) which isn't necessarily the ideal way to see one of my favorite punk acts. That said, the songs still hold up. Was also cool to see <a href="http://www.laurastevenson.net/">Laura Stevenson</a> filling in with him.</li>
</ul>
<p>I had to bail before Frank Turner in Boston because I had to get prepped for a presentation the next day, but I'm sure it was great.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/frank-turner-be-more-kind-tour/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/frank-turner-be-more-kind-tour/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In June I had the chance to see two dates of the Be More Kind tour with Frank Turner and the Sleeping Souls. Both shows had completely different and amazing sets of openers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 23, 2018 - Aragon Ballroom (Chicago)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://themenzingers.com/&quot;&gt;The Menzingers&lt;/a&gt; - Happy to finally get a chance to see these guys live after listening to them since Chamberlain Waits. Had the whole place singing along, even as openers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://luceromusic.com/&quot;&gt;Lucero&lt;/a&gt; - I&apos;ve seen Lucero before, so I knew they put on a great show and have been on the road long enough to have zero fucks left to give. Even knowing that, I was shocked that they came out and played their entire unreleased new album front to back. The new album sounds great, but would have been nice to hear a song or two I knew.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://frank-turner.com/&quot;&gt;Frank Turner and the Sleeping Souls&lt;/a&gt; - a surprisingly well oiled machine live. The stuff off of his new album Be More Kind sounded great live.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt;June 27, 2018 - Royale (Boston)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://restorations.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;Restorations&lt;/a&gt; - Double dipped on this tour via stubhub for a chance to see this band, and they put on a fantastic opening set. Can&apos;t recommend them enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jeffrosenstock.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;Jeff Rosenstock&lt;/a&gt; - since this was a one off gig he played the set acoustic (a little over half solo, the rest with some local friends backing him) which isn&apos;t necessarily the ideal way to see one of my favorite punk acts. That said, the songs still hold up. Was also cool to see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laurastevenson.net/&quot;&gt;Laura Stevenson&lt;/a&gt; filling in with him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to bail before Frank Turner in Boston because I had to get prepped for a presentation the next day, but I&apos;m sure it was great.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Design 4 Drupal Recap]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(Photo credit: Andy Olson)</em></p>
<p>Being back in Cambridge pretty much feels like being home for me, so I jumped at the chance to participate in <a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/">Design 4 Drupal</a> this year. While I currently live in the Chicago area, I grew up in Rhode Island and lived in Waltham, MA for about 5 years before heading midwest. Cambridge-wise I performed at <a href="http://www.improvboston.com/">ImprovBoston</a> for many years, and also did contract and part-time work for Harvard and MIT. Combine that with a total of <a href="https://www.hs2solutions.com/blog/design-4-drupal-conference-features-hs2-thought-leaders">four HS2 related talks</a>, keynotes from <a href="https://adactio.com/">Jeremy Keith</a> and <a href="https://dri.es/">Dries Buytaert</a> and the excitement levels for this one were super high.</p>
<p>Two keynotes from folks I follow closely were undeniably a big draw here, and they did not disappoint.</p>
<p><b>The Building Blocks Of The Indie Web</b></p>
<p>The concepts behind <a href="https://indieweb.org/">the indie web</a> aren't for everyone, at least not with the tools that exist today. But for me, having your own website and owning your own data are <a href="http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/to-pesos-or-to-posse-dries-buytaert/">a big motivator behind how I'm approaching this site</a> and there is quite a bit more that I'd like to do in the future. Jeremy's talk was a great introduction to the concepts that power the indie web, how they actually work, and what can be done to make this movement thrive. He's a really engaging speaker as well - I'd recommend both <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GZUq1kF4wXk">watching the recording</a> and also reading the <a href="https://adactio.com/journal/14074">recap of his Boston trip</a>.</p>
<p><b>Exploring the New Drupal Front-end with JavaScript</b></p>
<p>It was great getting a chance to see Dries speak in a less formal and non-DrupalCon Keynote environment. His presentation featured a nice balance between history and ongoing evolution of both Drupal and JavaScript. From the perspective of evolution, Dries outlined what he sees as the two main focus areas for Drupal 8:</p>
<ol>
<li>Making Drupal easier to use for both content creators and site builders.</li>
<li>Evolving Drupal into an API-first platform.</li> 
</ol>
<p>Drupal's JavaScript modernization efforts will continue to help evolve the robustness of Drupal's API, both by offering alternative formats to REST like JSON API and GraphQL, but also by providing API support for an alternative Drupal admin UI built in React.  Dries outlined a longer list of efforts in support of this JavaScript based administration interface - which had the positive side effect of benefiting all Decoupled Drupal builds.</p>
<p>Dries offered a straightforward rallying cry for how we can continue to allow Drupal to grow and thrive on a JavaScript dominated web - we need to find ways to get people outside of the Drupal community to think of Drupal as an option for storing and managing their data. One of my future goals as a speaker is to expand beyond the Drupal community, so it was nice to hear that I could align with this effort.</p>
<p>In response to some praise during the Q&A related to improvements in Drupal user experience, Dries was brutally honest about the fact that we still have a long way to go. In his opinion, ease of use is still the number one thing holding Drupal back, going as far as stating explicitly "I'm not satisfied with Drupal's ease of use." It would have been easy for him to accept the compliment on behalf of Drupal, but I think many in the design-focused audience would have found that disappointing. Hearing such an impassioned, clear counterpoint from Dries is likely to stand out in my mind for a long time.</p>
<p>Given all I've said, I doubt this would be surprising, but I think that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FCgPM5t7MHg">this talk is a must watch</a> for anyone invested in the future of Drupal.</p>
<p><b>Fellow HS2'ers at Design for Drupal</b></p>
<p>I was very happy to have a handful of friends from HS2 Solutions presenting at Design 4 Drupal as well.</p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/uxproject-strategy/effective-cross-functional-communication">Effective Cross Functional Communication</a></em></p>
<p>Amanda and Seth provided an insightful look at one of the hidden challenges of this profession - cross functional communication. The talk was full of thoughtful reminders (always assume positive intent, listen to understand - don't listen to interrupt) and just as impressively provided a great model for a seamless approach to co-presenting. I'll be looking back at this one when prepping for future joint talks. (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nud4i2-lIbY">Video</a>) </p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/case-studypanel/how-svgs-power-wilson-sporting-goods-product-configurator">How SVGs Power Wilson Sporting Goods Product Configurator</a></em></p>
<p>Projects like the Wilson product configurator are among the things that make me proud to work at HS2. Creating a UI to allow customers to design custom versions of uniforms and sporting equipment can seem simple, until you consider the sheer number of possible unique variations that need to be provided. Solving for the hidden complexity in a system like this is something that I find endlessly fascinating, and Andy did an excellent job explaining how it was done. (<a href= "https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dHNFVL8sTRY">Video</a>) </p>
<p><b>My Talks</b></p>
<p>I gave two talks for the first time which was pretty stressful, but I'm happy with how both turned out.</p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/uivisual-design/storybook-interactive-pattern-library-your-decoupled-applications">Storybook: An Interactive Pattern Library for Your Decoupled Applications</a></em></p>
<p>Prepping for this talk allowed me to go back and formalize some of the things I had learned about using Storybook as a development environment for React components. The biggest lesson learned for me was how much following a few conventions related to mocking data can streamline the setup and configuration process. I also continue to be impressed with how useful the addon ecosystem is and how well Storybook can inform testing.</p>

<p>Through follow up discussions with Andy I also spent some time thinking about how a tool like Storybook can fit into component-based JavaScript development workflows at HS2. I personally see Storybook as more of a development environment and less of a style guide (the workshop portion of <a href="http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/the-workshop-and-the-storefront/">Brad Frost’s ‘Workshop and Storefront’ concept</a>.) The finished components can then be consumed in their target applications alongside <a href="https://github.com/bradfrost/gatsby-style-guide-guide">a more formal statically generated style guide</a>. I'll be presenting this one again at <a href="https://www.drupalgovcon.org/">Drupal GovCon</a> in August and hope to incorporate a little more of these concepts into the talk.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NwZJ5M5tu7s?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p><em><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/theming/back-basics-drupal-8-theming">Back to Basics Drupal 8 Theming</a></em></p>
<p>I had intended for this to be a beginner talk, but I don't think it really ended up that way. Maybe beginner++?  I do think there is useful information for beginners in here, but I acknowledge that this would be a tough place to jump in. In any case, the process of putting this talk together and re-evaluating my workflow was an extremely useful exercise for me. I also heard feedback from more than one backend developer who attended that thought it was a nice overview. Hoping to refine this one and present it again. And maybe this time I'll try to not be quite as punchy and over caffeinated :)</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pDQ_NCxk8vA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p><b>Other Sessions I Enjoyed</b></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="Building a Living Style Guide with Herman - in Your Sass!">Building a Living Style Guide with Herman - in Your Sass!</a> - enjoyed learning about Herman, a living style guide tool with some great specialized Sass focused options. There did seem to be a surprising amount of overhead necessary to get it running though. Was also great getting a chance to meet Chris at this conference.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/site-building/meta-and-schema-defining-content-about-your-content">Meta and Schema: Defining the Content about your Content</a> - always enjoy watching Jim speak, and this was an extremely detailed overview in a topic I should be more of an expert in.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/case-studypanel/front-end-tooling-panel-discussion">Front-end Tooling: A Panel Discussion</a> - hearing three experts share their thoughts on this topic was a nice reminder that this really is difficult and constantly evolving (it isn't just me.) Also a nice reminder to finally try <a href="https://prettier.io/">Prettier</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Sessions I Hope to Follow Up On</b></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/uivisual-design/maintaining-design-consistency-across-every-channel">Maintaining Design Consistency Across Every Channel</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/site-building/estimates-expectations-and-evolution-during-projects-journey-rfp-release">Estimates, Expectations, and Evolution During a Project's Journey from RFP to Release</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/theming/next-gen-design-systems-pattern-lab-twig-and-web-components">Next Gen Design Systems with Pattern Lab, Twig, and Web Components</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/site-building/estimates-expectations-and-evolution-during-projects-journey-rfp-release">Estimates, Expectations, and Evolution During a Project's Journey from RFP to Release</a> - I've heard great things about this one from multiple Drupal events, and impressively this was successfully presented remotely at Design 4 Drupal.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Sprints</b></p>
<p>I worked on the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab">UI Patterns Pattern Lab</a> module - merged a pull request, responded to two issues (resolving one,) and got a few cleanup commits. I'm also hoping that the MacBook that had coffee spilled on it at the end of the day is still functioning.</p>
<p><b>Other Fun!</b></p>
<p>Dinners with friends and family, Drupal Karaoke (and <a href="https://www.mcdwayne.com/2018/07/02/design4drupal-2018/">sent Dwane on a walk I'll probably never hear the end of</a>,) saw Restorations and Jeff Rosenstock open for <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Bkk0sZOHcbt/">Frank Turner at Royale</a>, and repeatedly had some of my all time favorite iced coffee at Clover. Phew!</p>  
<p>Thanks to all at Design 4 Drupal, especially <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/leslieg">Leslie Glynn</a> who was extremely supportive and organized a great event. Hope to be back with the New England Drupal community soon.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/design-4-drupal-recap/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/design-4-drupal-recap/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Photo credit: Andy Olson)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being back in Cambridge pretty much feels like being home for me, so I jumped at the chance to participate in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/&quot;&gt;Design 4 Drupal&lt;/a&gt; this year. While I currently live in the Chicago area, I grew up in Rhode Island and lived in Waltham, MA for about 5 years before heading midwest. Cambridge-wise I performed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.improvboston.com/&quot;&gt;ImprovBoston&lt;/a&gt; for many years, and also did contract and part-time work for Harvard and MIT. Combine that with a total of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hs2solutions.com/blog/design-4-drupal-conference-features-hs2-thought-leaders&quot;&gt;four HS2 related talks&lt;/a&gt;, keynotes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Keith&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dri.es/&quot;&gt;Dries Buytaert&lt;/a&gt; and the excitement levels for this one were super high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two keynotes from folks I follow closely were undeniably a big draw here, and they did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Building Blocks Of The Indie Web&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concepts behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot;&gt;the indie web&lt;/a&gt; aren&apos;t for everyone, at least not with the tools that exist today. But for me, having your own website and owning your own data are &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/to-pesos-or-to-posse-dries-buytaert/&quot;&gt;a big motivator behind how I&apos;m approaching this site&lt;/a&gt; and there is quite a bit more that I&apos;d like to do in the future. Jeremy&apos;s talk was a great introduction to the concepts that power the indie web, how they actually work, and what can be done to make this movement thrive. He&apos;s a really engaging speaker as well - I&apos;d recommend both &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GZUq1kF4wXk&quot;&gt;watching the recording&lt;/a&gt; and also reading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://adactio.com/journal/14074&quot;&gt;recap of his Boston trip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exploring the New Drupal Front-end with JavaScript&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was great getting a chance to see Dries speak in a less formal and non-DrupalCon Keynote environment. His presentation featured a nice balance between history and ongoing evolution of both Drupal and JavaScript. From the perspective of evolution, Dries outlined what he sees as the two main focus areas for Drupal 8:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making Drupal easier to use for both content creators and site builders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolving Drupal into an API-first platform.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drupal&apos;s JavaScript modernization efforts will continue to help evolve the robustness of Drupal&apos;s API, both by offering alternative formats to REST like JSON API and GraphQL, but also by providing API support for an alternative Drupal admin UI built in React.  Dries outlined a longer list of efforts in support of this JavaScript based administration interface - which had the positive side effect of benefiting all Decoupled Drupal builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dries offered a straightforward rallying cry for how we can continue to allow Drupal to grow and thrive on a JavaScript dominated web - we need to find ways to get people outside of the Drupal community to think of Drupal as an option for storing and managing their data. One of my future goals as a speaker is to expand beyond the Drupal community, so it was nice to hear that I could align with this effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to some praise during the Q&amp;A related to improvements in Drupal user experience, Dries was brutally honest about the fact that we still have a long way to go. In his opinion, ease of use is still the number one thing holding Drupal back, going as far as stating explicitly &quot;I&apos;m not satisfied with Drupal&apos;s ease of use.&quot; It would have been easy for him to accept the compliment on behalf of Drupal, but I think many in the design-focused audience would have found that disappointing. Hearing such an impassioned, clear counterpoint from Dries is likely to stand out in my mind for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all I&apos;ve said, I doubt this would be surprising, but I think that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FCgPM5t7MHg&quot;&gt;this talk is a must watch&lt;/a&gt; for anyone invested in the future of Drupal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fellow HS2&apos;ers at Design for Drupal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very happy to have a handful of friends from HS2 Solutions presenting at Design 4 Drupal as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/uxproject-strategy/effective-cross-functional-communication&quot;&gt;Effective Cross Functional Communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda and Seth provided an insightful look at one of the hidden challenges of this profession - cross functional communication. The talk was full of thoughtful reminders (always assume positive intent, listen to understand - don&apos;t listen to interrupt) and just as impressively provided a great model for a seamless approach to co-presenting. I&apos;ll be looking back at this one when prepping for future joint talks. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nud4i2-lIbY&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/case-studypanel/how-svgs-power-wilson-sporting-goods-product-configurator&quot;&gt;How SVGs Power Wilson Sporting Goods Product Configurator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects like the Wilson product configurator are among the things that make me proud to work at HS2. Creating a UI to allow customers to design custom versions of uniforms and sporting equipment can seem simple, until you consider the sheer number of possible unique variations that need to be provided. Solving for the hidden complexity in a system like this is something that I find endlessly fascinating, and Andy did an excellent job explaining how it was done. (&lt;a href= &quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dHNFVL8sTRY&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;My Talks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave two talks for the first time which was pretty stressful, but I&apos;m happy with how both turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/uivisual-design/storybook-interactive-pattern-library-your-decoupled-applications&quot;&gt;Storybook: An Interactive Pattern Library for Your Decoupled Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepping for this talk allowed me to go back and formalize some of the things I had learned about using Storybook as a development environment for React components. The biggest lesson learned for me was how much following a few conventions related to mocking data can streamline the setup and configuration process. I also continue to be impressed with how useful the addon ecosystem is and how well Storybook can inform testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through follow up discussions with Andy I also spent some time thinking about how a tool like Storybook can fit into component-based JavaScript development workflows at HS2. I personally see Storybook as more of a development environment and less of a style guide (the workshop portion of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/the-workshop-and-the-storefront/&quot;&gt;Brad Frost’s ‘Workshop and Storefront’ concept&lt;/a&gt;.) The finished components can then be consumed in their target applications alongside &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bradfrost/gatsby-style-guide-guide&quot;&gt;a more formal statically generated style guide&lt;/a&gt;. I&apos;ll be presenting this one again at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupalgovcon.org/&quot;&gt;Drupal GovCon&lt;/a&gt; in August and hope to incorporate a little more of these concepts into the talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NwZJ5M5tu7s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/theming/back-basics-drupal-8-theming&quot;&gt;Back to Basics Drupal 8 Theming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had intended for this to be a beginner talk, but I don&apos;t think it really ended up that way. Maybe beginner++?  I do think there is useful information for beginners in here, but I acknowledge that this would be a tough place to jump in. In any case, the process of putting this talk together and re-evaluating my workflow was an extremely useful exercise for me. I also heard feedback from more than one backend developer who attended that thought it was a nice overview. Hoping to refine this one and present it again. And maybe this time I&apos;ll try to not be quite as punchy and over caffeinated :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pDQ_NCxk8vA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other Sessions I Enjoyed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;Building a Living Style Guide with Herman - in Your Sass!&quot;&gt;Building a Living Style Guide with Herman - in Your Sass!&lt;/a&gt; - enjoyed learning about Herman, a living style guide tool with some great specialized Sass focused options. There did seem to be a surprising amount of overhead necessary to get it running though. Was also great getting a chance to meet Chris at this conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/site-building/meta-and-schema-defining-content-about-your-content&quot;&gt;Meta and Schema: Defining the Content about your Content&lt;/a&gt; - always enjoy watching Jim speak, and this was an extremely detailed overview in a topic I should be more of an expert in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/case-studypanel/front-end-tooling-panel-discussion&quot;&gt;Front-end Tooling: A Panel Discussion&lt;/a&gt; - hearing three experts share their thoughts on this topic was a nice reminder that this really is difficult and constantly evolving (it isn&apos;t just me.) Also a nice reminder to finally try &lt;a href=&quot;https://prettier.io/&quot;&gt;Prettier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sessions I Hope to Follow Up On&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/uivisual-design/maintaining-design-consistency-across-every-channel&quot;&gt;Maintaining Design Consistency Across Every Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/site-building/estimates-expectations-and-evolution-during-projects-journey-rfp-release&quot;&gt;Estimates, Expectations, and Evolution During a Project&apos;s Journey from RFP to Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/theming/next-gen-design-systems-pattern-lab-twig-and-web-components&quot;&gt;Next Gen Design Systems with Pattern Lab, Twig, and Web Components&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.design4drupal.org/sessions/site-building/estimates-expectations-and-evolution-during-projects-journey-rfp-release&quot;&gt;Estimates, Expectations, and Evolution During a Project&apos;s Journey from RFP to Release&lt;/a&gt; - I&apos;ve heard great things about this one from multiple Drupal events, and impressively this was successfully presented remotely at Design 4 Drupal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sprints&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab&quot;&gt;UI Patterns Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt; module - merged a pull request, responded to two issues (resolving one,) and got a few cleanup commits. I&apos;m also hoping that the MacBook that had coffee spilled on it at the end of the day is still functioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other Fun!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinners with friends and family, Drupal Karaoke (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcdwayne.com/2018/07/02/design4drupal-2018/&quot;&gt;sent Dwane on a walk I&apos;ll probably never hear the end of&lt;/a&gt;,) saw Restorations and Jeff Rosenstock open for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bkk0sZOHcbt/&quot;&gt;Frank Turner at Royale&lt;/a&gt;, and repeatedly had some of my all time favorite iced coffee at Clover. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all at Design 4 Drupal, especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/leslieg&quot;&gt;Leslie Glynn&lt;/a&gt; who was extremely supportive and organized a great event. Hope to be back with the New England Drupal community soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Del Close Marathon Memories]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
During one Del Close Marathon, around 2005, someone within the Upright Citizen Brigade organization decided it would be a good idea to buy a motorized, rideable beer cooler for the event. ... All other particulars of this performance escape me, except for our decision that Matt Walsh should “jump” the motorized rideable beer cooler off a ramp, Evel Knievel–style. We furthermore decided that the ramp should consist of a board propped up on me as I lay on the floor.
</blockquote>
<p>To celebrate the Del Close Marathon this past weekend, Vulture has a great set of DCM memories from UCB performers. I was at the marathon with the motorized beer cooler, including the show with the so-called ramp jump. I'd always try to get in early enough on Friday so that I could be in the main theater for the UCB Four (often three given Amy Poehler's schedule.) Not sure I hit 10, but I think I topped out at either 8 or 9 long, sweaty lost weekends "performing" (huge air quotes there) at the Del Close Marathon.</p>
<p>Some other random memories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Performing improv on Unicycles to a packed theater with many folks sitting dangerously on the floor a little after midnight. (<a href="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1285/871054374_1a1c7513af_b.jpg">Here's a pic of the show from Boston</a> that indicates some of the chaos.)</li>
<li>Going up after Ed Helms and Sarah Sliverman in a prime slot in the main theater and bombing so hard that we spent most of the drive home talking about how we were all quitting improv.</li>
<li>The incredibly overwhelming years where the party space was in the halls behind the theater.</li>
<li>Performing multiple times to sleeping audience members.</li>
<li>Burning out on comedy and ditching the festival to spend the afternoon at a bar with a couple of friends, including one who didn't come for the festival at all.</li>
<li>Seeing the fascinatingly awful movie 'Lady in the Water' and then doing an improv set that frequently referenced it.</li>
<li>Walking at dawn to an early morning show past an empty Madison Square Garden area, and feeling like I was a survivor in a post apocalyptic world.</li>
<li>Blissfuly hungover Sunday train rides home.</li>
</ul>
<p>Aside from a recent exception, I don't perform improv anymore, but I always feel a twinge when I see all of the DCM action on social media. The marathon moving to LA next year makes sense, but is the end of an era for me. I'm sure it will find its way back home eventually.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/my-del-close-marathon-memories/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/my-del-close-marathon-memories/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
During one Del Close Marathon, around 2005, someone within the Upright Citizen Brigade organization decided it would be a good idea to buy a motorized, rideable beer cooler for the event. ... All other particulars of this performance escape me, except for our decision that Matt Walsh should “jump” the motorized rideable beer cooler off a ramp, Evel Knievel–style. We furthermore decided that the ramp should consist of a board propped up on me as I lay on the floor.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the Del Close Marathon this past weekend, Vulture has a great set of DCM memories from UCB performers. I was at the marathon with the motorized beer cooler, including the show with the so-called ramp jump. I&apos;d always try to get in early enough on Friday so that I could be in the main theater for the UCB Four (often three given Amy Poehler&apos;s schedule.) Not sure I hit 10, but I think I topped out at either 8 or 9 long, sweaty lost weekends &quot;performing&quot; (huge air quotes there) at the Del Close Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other random memories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing improv on Unicycles to a packed theater with many folks sitting dangerously on the floor a little after midnight. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1285/871054374_1a1c7513af_b.jpg&quot;&gt;Here&apos;s a pic of the show from Boston&lt;/a&gt; that indicates some of the chaos.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going up after Ed Helms and Sarah Sliverman in a prime slot in the main theater and bombing so hard that we spent most of the drive home talking about how we were all quitting improv.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The incredibly overwhelming years where the party space was in the halls behind the theater.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing multiple times to sleeping audience members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burning out on comedy and ditching the festival to spend the afternoon at a bar with a couple of friends, including one who didn&apos;t come for the festival at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing the fascinatingly awful movie &apos;Lady in the Water&apos; and then doing an improv set that frequently referenced it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walking at dawn to an early morning show past an empty Madison Square Garden area, and feeling like I was a survivor in a post apocalyptic world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blissfuly hungover Sunday train rides home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from a recent exception, I don&apos;t perform improv anymore, but I always feel a twinge when I see all of the DCM action on social media. The marathon moving to LA next year makes sense, but is the end of an era for me. I&apos;m sure it will find its way back home eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sometimes a Recruiter Reminds You That Your Pet Died]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I've got some good news and some bad news recruiter.  Good news: you got my attention by reading the <a href="/about">about page</a> on my website and using the subject line "Update on the Fish." Bad news: by asking "I noticed from the portfolio that you have (currently) two fish - is this up to date??" I now have to regretfully inform you that one of my fish has died. Related question: do you have any connections with people who are able to keep fish alive?</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/sometimes-a-recruiter-reminds-you-that-your-pet-died/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/sometimes-a-recruiter-reminds-you-that-your-pet-died/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve got some good news and some bad news recruiter.  Good news: you got my attention by reading the &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;about page&lt;/a&gt; on my website and using the subject line &quot;Update on the Fish.&quot; Bad news: by asking &quot;I noticed from the portfolio that you have (currently) two fish - is this up to date??&quot; I now have to regretfully inform you that one of my fish has died. Related question: do you have any connections with people who are able to keep fish alive?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hot JAMStack in React For Drupal Newsletter ]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>I've always found that one of the best ways to learn something new is to get my hands dirty and start writing code. But it also helps me to have a project to work on, and a goal in mind. You could always go the traditional route and build a to-do list. I need something that's going to hold my attention a bit longer though. With that in mind, here are a couple of ideas that have inspired me recently.</p>

<p><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React</a><br />
Brian Perry gave a talk at DrupalCon Nashville about how he created an application for visualizing trends in popular music using Drupal and React. It's an interesting example, and I love how he's taken something he's passionate about and turned it into a learning opportunity. Find something to play with in <a href="https://github.com/toddmotto/public-apis">this huge list of publicly available APIs</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Thanks to <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/eojthebrave">Joe Shindelar</a> and the folks at <a href="http://lullaboteducation.com/">Lullabot Education</a> for the nice shout out in the <a href="https://reactfordrupal.com/">React for Drupal</a> newsletter. Here's to hoping this project continues to be useful for people.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/hot-jamstack-in-react-for-drupal-newsletter/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/hot-jamstack-in-react-for-drupal-newsletter/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve always found that one of the best ways to learn something new is to get my hands dirty and start writing code. But it also helps me to have a project to work on, and a goal in mind. You could always go the traditional route and build a to-do list. I need something that&apos;s going to hold my attention a bit longer though. With that in mind, here are a couple of ideas that have inspired me recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Brian Perry gave a talk at DrupalCon Nashville about how he created an application for visualizing trends in popular music using Drupal and React. It&apos;s an interesting example, and I love how he&apos;s taken something he&apos;s passionate about and turned it into a learning opportunity. Find something to play with in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/toddmotto/public-apis&quot;&gt;this huge list of publicly available APIs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/eojthebrave&quot;&gt;Joe Shindelar&lt;/a&gt; and the folks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://lullaboteducation.com/&quot;&gt;Lullabot Education&lt;/a&gt; for the nice shout out in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactfordrupal.com/&quot;&gt;React for Drupal&lt;/a&gt; newsletter. Here&apos;s to hoping this project continues to be useful for people.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tome - A Drupal 8 Static Site Generator]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>With projects like <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.com/">Gatsby</a> continuing to grow, the static site generator trend does not seem to be going anywhere. While <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-source-drupal/">Gatsby can play nice with Drupal</a> (this site being an example,) the process could be a little easier. As a result, I was happy to see the announcement of <a href="https://tome.fyi/">Tome</a> yesterday.</p>

<p>Tome is a self described "static site generator lovingly crafted with Drupal 8." I think having a solid Drupal-only alternative could be really useful for folks who aren't ready to dive into something like React in order to use Gatsby. I ran through the <a href="https://tome.fyi/docs/getting-started/">getting started tutorial</a> and while I did run into <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/tome/issues/2980514">an issue with generated images</a>, I was impressed with what I saw so far.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/tome-a-drupal-8-static-site-generator/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/tome-a-drupal-8-static-site-generator/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;With projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; continuing to grow, the static site generator trend does not seem to be going anywhere. While &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-source-drupal/&quot;&gt;Gatsby can play nice with Drupal&lt;/a&gt; (this site being an example,) the process could be a little easier. As a result, I was happy to see the announcement of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tome.fyi/&quot;&gt;Tome&lt;/a&gt; yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tome is a self described &quot;static site generator lovingly crafted with Drupal 8.&quot; I think having a solid Drupal-only alternative could be really useful for folks who aren&apos;t ready to dive into something like React in order to use Gatsby. I ran through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tome.fyi/docs/getting-started/&quot;&gt;getting started tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and while I did run into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/tome/issues/2980514&quot;&gt;an issue with generated images&lt;/a&gt;, I was impressed with what I saw so far.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twin Cities Drupal Camp Recap]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Sure, I missed the Friday night camp party to go to the Twins game for Prince night, but how can I complain when I got this photo out of it?</p>

<p>I wasn't sure I was going to be able to make it to Twin Cities Drupal Camp this year as I had a little too much travel lined up. I even went as far as telling <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/stpaultim">Tim Erickson</a> at DrupalCon that I wasn't going to attend. However, after hearing that a few other HS2 folks would be submitting sessions I couldn't resist. I eventually decided that I'd lean into the Drupal Camp wave and attend as many as I could this season. So I walked into the University of St. Thomas atrium with my head held high, but as a dirty liar.</p>

<p>Once things kicked off, I was immediately glad that I had this change of heart. Twin Cities has a wonderful Drupal community with a camp that is well run and has been very supportive of me and <a href="http://2017.tcdrupal.org/session/user-onboarding-and-legend-zelda">my craziest ideas</a> for a few years now. I would have been really sad to have missed it. I was even able to continue the good community vibes with the first session of the camp I attended - <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/drupal-and-music-industry-learning-our-success">Drupal and the Music Industry - Learning from our Success</a>. Hearing about all of the music industry sites that are or have been powered by Drupal was a nice reminder that our work can impact the world at large, and even sites our parents and/or kids use. Who needs whitehouse.gov when we've got Justin Bieber?</p>

<p>The camp also served as a nice opportunity to catch up with past and present co-workers, many who were giving talks.</p>

<ul>
<li>Was able to catch Will Long's <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/next-level-twig-extensions">Next Level Twig: Extensions</a> which gave a nice concise overview of popular twig extensions in the contrib space and examples of how to implement your own.</li>
<li>Will was also part of the <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/civicrm-secrets-drupalers">CiviCRM Secrets for Drupalers</a> session which provided my first introduction to the <a href="https://civicrm.org/">CiviCRM</a> project and some background on the Drupal integration that the folks at <a href="https://www.mydropwizard.com/">myDropWizard</a> are building for it.</li>
<li>In <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/drupal-8-migrate-its-not-rocket-science">Drupal 8 Migrate: It's not rocket science...</a> Jack Franks provided one of his typically fun and engaging live demos - this time doing live migrations against NASA APIs. He also gets bonus points for rolling with his computer freezing mid presentation, and also incorporating a partial config import into the demo based on one of my comments during the Q&A.</li>
<li>Finally current HS2 colleague Chris Greatens presented <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/hello-username-personalization-everyone">Hello [user:name]: Personalization for Everyone</a> which provided an excellent overview of personalization concepts, along with a look at some examples of some poorly executed uses of personalization. Those personalization missteps inspired quite a bit of discussion from attendees in the Q&A.</li>
</ul>

<p><em><a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/component-based-theming-ui-patterns-and-pattern-lab">Component Based Theming With UI Patterns and Pattern Lab</a></em></p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bKD7QZVq9SM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>This was my second time in 7 days speaking about the UI Patterns module, but I added a little Pattern Lab specific content this time around.  It was another <a href="http://shellmultimedia.com/2018-tcdrupal/hadc24fb8#hadc24fb8">well attended</a> UI Patterns talk which tells me that more folks are understanding the value in the functionality offered by the UI Patterns module, and also that pattern library driven theming workflows still continue to gain popularity in the Drupal community. Thanks to all who attended, to Michelle for <a href="http://shellmultimedia.com/2018-tcdrupal/hadc24fb7#hadc24fb7">this nice photo</a>, and also to <a href="https://www.mediacurrent.com/who-we-are/team/eric-huffman/">Eric from Mediacurrent</a> who I had a chance to walk through the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab">UI Patterns Pattern Lab</a> module during a quiet Saturday AM BOF block.</p>

<p>Also in the general neighborhood of design components I sat in on <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/stevector">Steve Persch's</a> session <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/everything-block-how-wordpress-rewrote-wysiwyg">Everything is a Block: How WordPress Rewrote the WYSIWYG</a>. It shared some overlap with his State of Wordpress session from DrupalCon but dove even deeper into the new hotness that is the Gutenberg editor. While I have some issues with the underlying structure of Gutenberg content (tons of content jammed into a body field,) the upsides to a consistent block based approach in the editor resonated with me.</p>

<p>Given that, I asked Steve how he thought we could move to a more consistent use of blocks in Drupal. With all of the possible approaches to this problem in Drupal, he thought that the community needs to align on the things we want to stop using. For him in the past his approach was based on layout plugins (which aligns well with the experimental layout builder module now in Drupal Core.) Alongside this layout based approach he also focused on limiting preprocessing as much as possible so that the admin UI could accurately reflect what ends up rendered on the front end. The latter point especially resonated with me as it is a disadvantage of the common Twig mapping approach to component based theming that I think can be improved by the UI Patterns module or something like it. Speaking of that, thanks to Steve for giving a nice shout out to my UI Patterns presentation during his talk.</p>

<p>The last session I caught at the camp was <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/conscious-uncoupling-drupal-8-meets-metalsmith">Conscious Uncoupling -Drupal 8 meets Metalsmith</a>. I was already familiar with many of the concepts here through my experimentation with Drupal and GatsbyJS, but it was great to hear someone else's positive experiences with the JAM Stack and decoupled Drupal. It also me amped to finally try Netlify, which I ended up liking quite a bit.</p>

<p>A few talks I missed but want to go back to:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/progressive-decoupling-case-study-pri">Progressive Decoupling: A case study with PRI</a></li>
<li><a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/easy-flexible-and-accurate-drupal-8-search-dr-seuss-and-search-api">Easy, Flexible and Accurate Drupal 8 Search with Dr. Seuss and Search API</a></li>
<li><a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/drupal-and-without-react-head-headless-comparison">Drupal with and without React, a head to headless comparison</a></li>
</ul>

<p>See you next year Twin Cities.  I'll just leave this here.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">So happy to get a chance to see my favorite <a href="https://twitter.com/TCDrupal?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@TCDrupal</a> friends again this year <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TCDrupal?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TCDrupal</a> <a href="https://t.co/XWlcF7Vh5X">pic.twitter.com/XWlcF7Vh5X</a></p>&mdash; Brian Perry (@bricomedy) <a href="https://twitter.com/bricomedy/status/1005539243823857664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 9, 2018</a></blockquote>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/twin-cities-drupal-camp-recap/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/twin-cities-drupal-camp-recap/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Sure, I missed the Friday night camp party to go to the Twins game for Prince night, but how can I complain when I got this photo out of it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&apos;t sure I was going to be able to make it to Twin Cities Drupal Camp this year as I had a little too much travel lined up. I even went as far as telling &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/stpaultim&quot;&gt;Tim Erickson&lt;/a&gt; at DrupalCon that I wasn&apos;t going to attend. However, after hearing that a few other HS2 folks would be submitting sessions I couldn&apos;t resist. I eventually decided that I&apos;d lean into the Drupal Camp wave and attend as many as I could this season. So I walked into the University of St. Thomas atrium with my head held high, but as a dirty liar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once things kicked off, I was immediately glad that I had this change of heart. Twin Cities has a wonderful Drupal community with a camp that is well run and has been very supportive of me and &lt;a href=&quot;http://2017.tcdrupal.org/session/user-onboarding-and-legend-zelda&quot;&gt;my craziest ideas&lt;/a&gt; for a few years now. I would have been really sad to have missed it. I was even able to continue the good community vibes with the first session of the camp I attended - &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/drupal-and-music-industry-learning-our-success&quot;&gt;Drupal and the Music Industry - Learning from our Success&lt;/a&gt;. Hearing about all of the music industry sites that are or have been powered by Drupal was a nice reminder that our work can impact the world at large, and even sites our parents and/or kids use. Who needs whitehouse.gov when we&apos;ve got Justin Bieber?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camp also served as a nice opportunity to catch up with past and present co-workers, many who were giving talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was able to catch Will Long&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/next-level-twig-extensions&quot;&gt;Next Level Twig: Extensions&lt;/a&gt; which gave a nice concise overview of popular twig extensions in the contrib space and examples of how to implement your own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will was also part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/civicrm-secrets-drupalers&quot;&gt;CiviCRM Secrets for Drupalers&lt;/a&gt; session which provided my first introduction to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://civicrm.org/&quot;&gt;CiviCRM&lt;/a&gt; project and some background on the Drupal integration that the folks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mydropwizard.com/&quot;&gt;myDropWizard&lt;/a&gt; are building for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/drupal-8-migrate-its-not-rocket-science&quot;&gt;Drupal 8 Migrate: It&apos;s not rocket science...&lt;/a&gt; Jack Franks provided one of his typically fun and engaging live demos - this time doing live migrations against NASA APIs. He also gets bonus points for rolling with his computer freezing mid presentation, and also incorporating a partial config import into the demo based on one of my comments during the Q&amp;A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally current HS2 colleague Chris Greatens presented &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/hello-username-personalization-everyone&quot;&gt;Hello [user:name]: Personalization for Everyone&lt;/a&gt; which provided an excellent overview of personalization concepts, along with a look at some examples of some poorly executed uses of personalization. Those personalization missteps inspired quite a bit of discussion from attendees in the Q&amp;A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/component-based-theming-ui-patterns-and-pattern-lab&quot;&gt;Component Based Theming With UI Patterns and Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bKD7QZVq9SM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my second time in 7 days speaking about the UI Patterns module, but I added a little Pattern Lab specific content this time around.  It was another &lt;a href=&quot;http://shellmultimedia.com/2018-tcdrupal/hadc24fb8#hadc24fb8&quot;&gt;well attended&lt;/a&gt; UI Patterns talk which tells me that more folks are understanding the value in the functionality offered by the UI Patterns module, and also that pattern library driven theming workflows still continue to gain popularity in the Drupal community. Thanks to all who attended, to Michelle for &lt;a href=&quot;http://shellmultimedia.com/2018-tcdrupal/hadc24fb7#hadc24fb7&quot;&gt;this nice photo&lt;/a&gt;, and also to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediacurrent.com/who-we-are/team/eric-huffman/&quot;&gt;Eric from Mediacurrent&lt;/a&gt; who I had a chance to walk through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab&quot;&gt;UI Patterns Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt; module during a quiet Saturday AM BOF block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in the general neighborhood of design components I sat in on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/stevector&quot;&gt;Steve Persch&apos;s&lt;/a&gt; session &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/everything-block-how-wordpress-rewrote-wysiwyg&quot;&gt;Everything is a Block: How WordPress Rewrote the WYSIWYG&lt;/a&gt;. It shared some overlap with his State of Wordpress session from DrupalCon but dove even deeper into the new hotness that is the Gutenberg editor. While I have some issues with the underlying structure of Gutenberg content (tons of content jammed into a body field,) the upsides to a consistent block based approach in the editor resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that, I asked Steve how he thought we could move to a more consistent use of blocks in Drupal. With all of the possible approaches to this problem in Drupal, he thought that the community needs to align on the things we want to stop using. For him in the past his approach was based on layout plugins (which aligns well with the experimental layout builder module now in Drupal Core.) Alongside this layout based approach he also focused on limiting preprocessing as much as possible so that the admin UI could accurately reflect what ends up rendered on the front end. The latter point especially resonated with me as it is a disadvantage of the common Twig mapping approach to component based theming that I think can be improved by the UI Patterns module or something like it. Speaking of that, thanks to Steve for giving a nice shout out to my UI Patterns presentation during his talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last session I caught at the camp was &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/conscious-uncoupling-drupal-8-meets-metalsmith&quot;&gt;Conscious Uncoupling -Drupal 8 meets Metalsmith&lt;/a&gt;. I was already familiar with many of the concepts here through my experimentation with Drupal and GatsbyJS, but it was great to hear someone else&apos;s positive experiences with the JAM Stack and decoupled Drupal. It also me amped to finally try Netlify, which I ended up liking quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few talks I missed but want to go back to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/progressive-decoupling-case-study-pri&quot;&gt;Progressive Decoupling: A case study with PRI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/easy-flexible-and-accurate-drupal-8-search-dr-seuss-and-search-api&quot;&gt;Easy, Flexible and Accurate Drupal 8 Search with Dr. Seuss and Search API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/session/drupal-and-without-react-head-headless-comparison&quot;&gt;Drupal with and without React, a head to headless comparison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next year Twin Cities.  I&apos;ll just leave this here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;So happy to get a chance to see my favorite &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TCDrupal?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@TCDrupal&lt;/a&gt; friends again this year &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/TCDrupal?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#TCDrupal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/XWlcF7Vh5X&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/XWlcF7Vh5X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brian Perry (@bricomedy) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bricomedy/status/1005539243823857664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 9, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Approach to PatternLab - Mark Conroy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>When I changed the conversation and started talking about ‘Building Blocks’ (what we call our Drupal paragraph types), site blocks (Drupal's search block, branding block), display types (Drupal's view modes such as teaser, search result), etc, they immediately understood.</blockquote>
<p>I'm setting up some front end tooling for an upcoming project and was also considering not using the atoms/molecules/organism naming conventions this time around. My naming conventions will likely vary based on the approach to the build, but the general approach here makes a lot of sense to me. Not surprised that it makes sense to clients as well.</p>
<blockquote>After that, I have Backstop.js set up to regression test all of these, so each time I create a new component I can quickly run the visual regression tests and check that nothing has broken. Since all my CSS/JS is scoped to each individual component, it's rare if something is.</blockquote>
<p>This. For this next build I was planning on having full visual regression testing coverage in the pattern library and then some sampling in Drupal, most likely assisted by the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/backstop_generator">Backstop Generator</a> module.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/my-approach-to-patternlab-mark-conroy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/my-approach-to-patternlab-mark-conroy/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;When I changed the conversation and started talking about ‘Building Blocks’ (what we call our Drupal paragraph types), site blocks (Drupal&apos;s search block, branding block), display types (Drupal&apos;s view modes such as teaser, search result), etc, they immediately understood.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m setting up some front end tooling for an upcoming project and was also considering not using the atoms/molecules/organism naming conventions this time around. My naming conventions will likely vary based on the approach to the build, but the general approach here makes a lot of sense to me. Not surprised that it makes sense to clients as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;After that, I have Backstop.js set up to regression test all of these, so each time I create a new component I can quickly run the visual regression tests and check that nothing has broken. Since all my CSS/JS is scoped to each individual component, it&apos;s rare if something is.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This. For this next build I was planning on having full visual regression testing coverage in the pattern library and then some sampling in Drupal, most likely assisted by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/backstop_generator&quot;&gt;Backstop Generator&lt;/a&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A First Taste of Netlify]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As I've been learning about <a href="https://jamstack.org/">the JAMstack</a> I've often heard really good things about using <a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify</a> for hosting. I had a chance to try it out yesterday and I must say that the hype seems pretty warranted.</p>
<p>I often call my blog the least important site on the internet, but the real winner of that award is <a href="http://www.campperry.fun/">Camp Perry</a>, a blog that I created as a joke for the unofficial neighborhood camp that happens in my back yard every summer. I wanted to move the blog to Gatsby and also take better advantage of the campperry.fun domain than I could on my current Github Pages configuration. Seemed like as good an excuse as any to try out Netlify. After granting access to my github repo, Netlify was able to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Automatically determine that I had a Gatsby site, and configure the build process accordingly</li>
<li>Deploy a new build whenever a commit was made to the master branch</li>
<li>For each new pull request, create a deploy preview site that I could use to sanity check my changes</li>
<li>Use my custom domain (this took a little configuration and was the hardest part, but mainly because I'm not great at domain stuff)</li>
</ul>
<p>All of that in a few minutes, and on the free tier. They also offer one click https, which I haven't gotten around to yet. Well worth checking out if you're looking for a place to host a static site build. I'd like to migrate this site to Netlify at some point as well to take advantage of some of the build automation and also https.</p>
<p><em>Update</em>: with my custom domain stuff all squared away I was able to try the one click https features. One click to enable https via letsencrypt, a second click to force https on the site. Took about 90 seconds start to finish. And Netlify will autorenew my letsencrypt certificate before it expires. Pretty amazing.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/a-first-taste-of-netlify/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/a-first-taste-of-netlify/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As I&apos;ve been learning about &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamstack.org/&quot;&gt;the JAMstack&lt;/a&gt; I&apos;ve often heard really good things about using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; for hosting. I had a chance to try it out yesterday and I must say that the hype seems pretty warranted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often call my blog the least important site on the internet, but the real winner of that award is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campperry.fun/&quot;&gt;Camp Perry&lt;/a&gt;, a blog that I created as a joke for the unofficial neighborhood camp that happens in my back yard every summer. I wanted to move the blog to Gatsby and also take better advantage of the campperry.fun domain than I could on my current Github Pages configuration. Seemed like as good an excuse as any to try out Netlify. After granting access to my github repo, Netlify was able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically determine that I had a Gatsby site, and configure the build process accordingly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy a new build whenever a commit was made to the master branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each new pull request, create a deploy preview site that I could use to sanity check my changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use my custom domain (this took a little configuration and was the hardest part, but mainly because I&apos;m not great at domain stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of that in a few minutes, and on the free tier. They also offer one click https, which I haven&apos;t gotten around to yet. Well worth checking out if you&apos;re looking for a place to host a static site build. I&apos;d like to migrate this site to Netlify at some point as well to take advantage of some of the build automation and also https.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: with my custom domain stuff all squared away I was able to try the one click https features. One click to enable https via letsencrypt, a second click to force https on the site. Took about 90 seconds start to finish. And Netlify will autorenew my letsencrypt certificate before it expires. Pretty amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Texas Camp Recap]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Photo by <a href="https://www.flickr.com/people/155787132@N07/">Yes Moon</a></p>

<p>Had an excellent, jam packed time at <a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/">Texas Camp</a> in Austin. It was an extremely well organized event attended by a bunch of super engaged and friendly Drupalers. A bit of a short trip for me as I had tickets to see <a href="https://www.hdtgminfo.com/">How Did This Get Made</a> back home on Saturday night, but that just resulted in things being focused around a couple of clear themes.</p>

<p><b>Visual Regression Testing</b></p>

<p>Visual Regression Testing is a topic I’ve been interested in quite a while now, but I’ve fallen out of practice as of late. I was really excited to see that there was a bunch of content on visual regression testing planned for the camp, much of which was focused around <a href="https://garris.github.io/BackstopJS/">BackstopJS</a>. I’ve tried a number of other solutions in the past (<a href="https://github.com/BBC-News/wraith">Wraith</a>, <a href="https://github.com/HuddleEng/PhantomCSS">PhantomCSS</a>, <a href="http://webdriver.io/">WebDriverIO</a>) but not Backstop JS which seems to be gaining momentum in the Drupal community.</p>

<p>On Thursday the folks at <a href="http://pantheon.io/">Pantheon</a> held a training session on BackstopJS, which I attended.  It provided a great overview of how they use the tool, along with some example repositories for learning. By the end of the training I had completed a first pass at adding a suite of regression tests to this blog. I would have liked to see a little more content in the training about the general functionality of BackstopJS rather than the Pantheon team’s use cases, but any training where I can walk out with a real world example implemented is a big win.</p>

<p>Continuing on the Backstop train I also doubled down and attended <a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/deploy-without-fear--visual-regression-testing-with-backstopjs-is-here">Ryan Bateman from Hook 42’s session on BackstopJS</a>. He provided a little more of the general functional overview that I was looking for after the training, and also talked about the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/backstop_generator">Backstop Generator</a> module that he had recently created. Backstop generator allows you to quickly create a backstop.json file that tests against specific pages on your site and/or a random selection of pages. Seems like a great way for Drupal projects to take advantage of BackstopJS with very little effort. It was also great getting a chance to talk with Ryan later on in the camp - I think he stands as the only Alaskan Drupalist I’ve ever met.</p>

<p>Due to travel I wasn’t able to catch David Stinemetze from Rackspace’s related <a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/archiving-and-visual-regression-using-drupal-8">Archiving and Visual Regression Using Drupal 8</a> session, but I’m planning on catching up on the video later.<p>

<p><b>Community</b></p>

<p>Texas Camp featured two very excellent keynotes that I was lucky enough to enjoy over breakfast burritos. Both are very much worth watching, so rather than try to recap, I’ll just paraphrase a few things that really stuck with me.</p>

<p>Nikki Stevens - <a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/happenings/keynote-breaking-the-binary-the-politics-of-code-and-inclusivity-in-technology">Breaking the Binary: The Politics of Code and Inclusivity in Technology</a></p>

<ul>
<li>Diversity is being invited to the party. Inclusion is being asked to dance.</li>
<li>Small choices matter and create new futures.</li>
<li>Forms on a website can influence real world behavior.</li>
</ul>

<p>Michael Schmid - <a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/happenings/keynote-the-future-of-drupal">The Future of Drupal</a></p>

<ul>
<li>Change is what keeps us alive.</li>
<li>JavaScript is taking over the web.</li>
<li>The market is (Squarespace, Wix, etc.) is pushing us in the direction of 'ambitious digital experiences'</li>
</ul>

<p><b>A Whole Bunch of Me Talking at People on Friday</b></p>

<p>I was initially scheduled to do my UI Patterns Talk, but was also asked to fill in for a presenter who was unable to attend.  As a result I got to give two talks in a single afternoon. This is fine for me because I love hearing myself talk, but to the brave souls who attended both of my sessions - I salute you.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/component-based-theming-with-ui-patterns">Component Based Theming With UI Patterns</a></em></p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xXt3v3FSxss?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Was exceptionally happy with the lively Q&A that followed the session.  Even if you've heard me give this talk before, I'd encourage you to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xXt3v3FSxss&feature=youtu.be&t=42m42s">jump to the Q&A at the end</a>.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-a-music-discovery-app-with-drupal-and-react">Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React</a></em></p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZzDs3hGx3zY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>It was fun revisiting this talk after DrupalCon, but I was especially excited to hear from people who either have, or were planning to use the examples in this project to learn more about decoupled Drupal and React. That was main motivation behind the talk in the first place, so I'm extremely happy that this project may have helped a few people find a starting point to experiment with decoupled Drupal and React.</p>

<p><b>Other Sessions</b></p>

<p>I also caught a handful of other great talks.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/web-accessibility-tips-and-tools">Web Accessibility Tips and Tools</a> - provided an excellent overview of a11y resources, many of which are <a href="http://bit.ly/2swdwj4">outlined in this google doc</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/manifestodriven-development">Manifesto-Driven Development</a> - an interesting look at influential tech manifestos and how you could use one to define the direction of a project.  Thinking about writing one for an upcoming project.</li>
<li><a href="https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/decoupling-edutopiaorg">Decoupling Edutopia.org</a>
 - a fascinating look at a complicated, highly performant decoupled build. I was impressed by some of the technical solutions but left wondering if the effort outweighed the benefit in this case.</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Fun!</b></p>

<p>Had some great BBQ and craft beer at the after parties, and can't stress enough how convenient it was having breakfast tacos around to start the day. And then Saturday night I met up with some old Boston friends and did the tourist-y <a href="http://www.batsinaustin.com/">bat bridge thing</a>, saw a fun band called <a href="http://www.quietcompanymusic.com/">Quiet Company</a> play at Stubbs BBQ, and closed out the night with some Austin food trucks.</p>

<p>All in all, a great trip. And I barely got this post online before the end of <a href="https://2018.tcdrupal.org/">the next camp on my list</a>.</p> ]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/texas-camp-recap/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/texas-camp-recap/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/people/155787132@N07/&quot;&gt;Yes Moon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had an excellent, jam packed time at &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/&quot;&gt;Texas Camp&lt;/a&gt; in Austin. It was an extremely well organized event attended by a bunch of super engaged and friendly Drupalers. A bit of a short trip for me as I had tickets to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdtgminfo.com/&quot;&gt;How Did This Get Made&lt;/a&gt; back home on Saturday night, but that just resulted in things being focused around a couple of clear themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Visual Regression Testing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Regression Testing is a topic I’ve been interested in quite a while now, but I’ve fallen out of practice as of late. I was really excited to see that there was a bunch of content on visual regression testing planned for the camp, much of which was focused around &lt;a href=&quot;https://garris.github.io/BackstopJS/&quot;&gt;BackstopJS&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve tried a number of other solutions in the past (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BBC-News/wraith&quot;&gt;Wraith&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HuddleEng/PhantomCSS&quot;&gt;PhantomCSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://webdriver.io/&quot;&gt;WebDriverIO&lt;/a&gt;) but not Backstop JS which seems to be gaining momentum in the Drupal community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday the folks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://pantheon.io/&quot;&gt;Pantheon&lt;/a&gt; held a training session on BackstopJS, which I attended.  It provided a great overview of how they use the tool, along with some example repositories for learning. By the end of the training I had completed a first pass at adding a suite of regression tests to this blog. I would have liked to see a little more content in the training about the general functionality of BackstopJS rather than the Pantheon team’s use cases, but any training where I can walk out with a real world example implemented is a big win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing on the Backstop train I also doubled down and attended &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/deploy-without-fear--visual-regression-testing-with-backstopjs-is-here&quot;&gt;Ryan Bateman from Hook 42’s session on BackstopJS&lt;/a&gt;. He provided a little more of the general functional overview that I was looking for after the training, and also talked about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/backstop_generator&quot;&gt;Backstop Generator&lt;/a&gt; module that he had recently created. Backstop generator allows you to quickly create a backstop.json file that tests against specific pages on your site and/or a random selection of pages. Seems like a great way for Drupal projects to take advantage of BackstopJS with very little effort. It was also great getting a chance to talk with Ryan later on in the camp - I think he stands as the only Alaskan Drupalist I’ve ever met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to travel I wasn’t able to catch David Stinemetze from Rackspace’s related &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/archiving-and-visual-regression-using-drupal-8&quot;&gt;Archiving and Visual Regression Using Drupal 8&lt;/a&gt; session, but I’m planning on catching up on the video later.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Community&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Texas Camp featured two very excellent keynotes that I was lucky enough to enjoy over breakfast burritos. Both are very much worth watching, so rather than try to recap, I’ll just paraphrase a few things that really stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikki Stevens - &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/happenings/keynote-breaking-the-binary-the-politics-of-code-and-inclusivity-in-technology&quot;&gt;Breaking the Binary: The Politics of Code and Inclusivity in Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diversity is being invited to the party. Inclusion is being asked to dance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small choices matter and create new futures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forms on a website can influence real world behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Schmid - &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/happenings/keynote-the-future-of-drupal&quot;&gt;The Future of Drupal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change is what keeps us alive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JavaScript is taking over the web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The market is (Squarespace, Wix, etc.) is pushing us in the direction of &apos;ambitious digital experiences&apos;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Whole Bunch of Me Talking at People on Friday&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was initially scheduled to do my UI Patterns Talk, but was also asked to fill in for a presenter who was unable to attend.  As a result I got to give two talks in a single afternoon. This is fine for me because I love hearing myself talk, but to the brave souls who attended both of my sessions - I salute you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/component-based-theming-with-ui-patterns&quot;&gt;Component Based Theming With UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xXt3v3FSxss?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was exceptionally happy with the lively Q&amp;A that followed the session.  Even if you&apos;ve heard me give this talk before, I&apos;d encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xXt3v3FSxss&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=42m42s&quot;&gt;jump to the Q&amp;A at the end&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-a-music-discovery-app-with-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZzDs3hGx3zY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun revisiting this talk after DrupalCon, but I was especially excited to hear from people who either have, or were planning to use the examples in this project to learn more about decoupled Drupal and React. That was main motivation behind the talk in the first place, so I&apos;m extremely happy that this project may have helped a few people find a starting point to experiment with decoupled Drupal and React.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other Sessions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also caught a handful of other great talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/web-accessibility-tips-and-tools&quot;&gt;Web Accessibility Tips and Tools&lt;/a&gt; - provided an excellent overview of a11y resources, many of which are &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2swdwj4&quot;&gt;outlined in this google doc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/manifestodriven-development&quot;&gt;Manifesto-Driven Development&lt;/a&gt; - an interesting look at influential tech manifestos and how you could use one to define the direction of a project.  Thinking about writing one for an upcoming project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.texascamp.org/sessions/decoupling-edutopiaorg&quot;&gt;Decoupling Edutopia.org&lt;/a&gt;
 - a fascinating look at a complicated, highly performant decoupled build. I was impressed by some of the technical solutions but left wondering if the effort outweighed the benefit in this case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fun!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had some great BBQ and craft beer at the after parties, and can&apos;t stress enough how convenient it was having breakfast tacos around to start the day. And then Saturday night I met up with some old Boston friends and did the tourist-y &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.batsinaustin.com/&quot;&gt;bat bridge thing&lt;/a&gt;, saw a fun band called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quietcompanymusic.com/&quot;&gt;Quiet Company&lt;/a&gt; play at Stubbs BBQ, and closed out the night with some Austin food trucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, a great trip. And I barely got this post online before the end of &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018.tcdrupal.org/&quot;&gt;the next camp on my list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[World wide wrist - Ethan Marcotte]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<a href="https://twitter.com/jensimmons/status/1003703375656087553">Jen Simmons’s suggestion</a> is spot-on: it just got a <em>lot</em> more important to design from a sensible, small screen-friendly document structure built atop semantic HTML.
</blockquote>
<p>I'm less excited about WebKit coming to watchOS than I am about the overall impact it will have. The more we focus on developing experiences that can be consumed at any size on any fidelity device, the better the web will become.</p>
<p>Nice <a href="https://erikrunyon.com/2018/06/designing-web-content-for-watchos/">post from Erik Runyon about some of the technical specifics</a> as well.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/world-wide-wrist-ethan-marcotte/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/world-wide-wrist-ethan-marcotte/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jensimmons/status/1003703375656087553&quot;&gt;Jen Simmons’s suggestion&lt;/a&gt; is spot-on: it just got a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more important to design from a sensible, small screen-friendly document structure built atop semantic HTML.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m less excited about WebKit coming to watchOS than I am about the overall impact it will have. The more we focus on developing experiences that can be consumed at any size on any fidelity device, the better the web will become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://erikrunyon.com/2018/06/designing-web-content-for-watchos/&quot;&gt;post from Erik Runyon about some of the technical specifics&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[When NOT to Use a Design System - Sparkbox]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Sometimes, a CMS gets built and the work is done. It gets used by content editors and is occasionally upgraded, but the development team and budgets are reallocated to other priorities, and the world moves on. This pattern is especially common with time-sensitive projects (event websites, marketing campaigns, etc.).</p>
<p>Design systems don’t make sense here because a design system demonstrates its value in times of active development. It’s when a designer is working on a new notification message and needs to know what colors to use. Or when a developer is building a new form and needs to see what field types already exist.</p>
<p>If you don’t anticipate a lot of new development on a project, then a robust design system may not make sense.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Had some related discussion in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xXt3v3FSxss&feature=youtu.be&t=42m42s">the Q&A during during my UI Patterns session at Texas Camp</a> this weekend - specifically on the actual value of creating an external pattern library in a typical Drupal project. I'm a believer that even just the opportunities to decouple front end and backend efforts can be worth the effort in many projects, but I also agree that you need to sensible in the amount of effort that gets invested into the pattern library. If the pattern library starts to feel like its own product, you might be going overboard. This post encapsulates those concerns pretty nicely.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/when-not-to-use-a-design-system-sparkbox/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/when-not-to-use-a-design-system-sparkbox/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a CMS gets built and the work is done. It gets used by content editors and is occasionally upgraded, but the development team and budgets are reallocated to other priorities, and the world moves on. This pattern is especially common with time-sensitive projects (event websites, marketing campaigns, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design systems don’t make sense here because a design system demonstrates its value in times of active development. It’s when a designer is working on a new notification message and needs to know what colors to use. Or when a developer is building a new form and needs to see what field types already exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t anticipate a lot of new development on a project, then a robust design system may not make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had some related discussion in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xXt3v3FSxss&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=42m42s&quot;&gt;the Q&amp;A during during my UI Patterns session at Texas Camp&lt;/a&gt; this weekend - specifically on the actual value of creating an external pattern library in a typical Drupal project. I&apos;m a believer that even just the opportunities to decouple front end and backend efforts can be worth the effort in many projects, but I also agree that you need to sensible in the amount of effort that gets invested into the pattern library. If the pattern library starts to feel like its own product, you might be going overboard. This post encapsulates those concerns pretty nicely.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[UI Patterns Pattern Lab and a Call for Help]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>tldr; I’ve recently been working on the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab">UI Patterns Pattern Lab</a> module which automatically discovers components in a Pattern Lab instance for use with Drupal. I’m looking to test it with a variety of Pattern Lab instances - <a href-"https://github.com/backlineint/ui_patterns_pattern_lab/issues/2">can you help</a>?</em></p>

<p>If we’ve run into each other at Drupal camps over the past couple of years, you’ve probably heard me talk about component based development and most likely also the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns">UI Patterns Module</a>. I’m a big supporter of a pattern library driven approach to building a Drupal site, but also feel that some common practices can be complicated - especially for those new to the approach or those not focused on the front end. In my opinion, UI Patterns can reduce that complexity quite a bit.</p>

<p>When the UI Patterns module came along it seemed too good to be true. It allowed patterns to be formally defined as Drupal plugins and took the data mapping that was commonly happening behind the scenes in Twig templates and exposed these in the admin UI where a wider audience could configure and understand them.  But if you were using an external pattern library in your project, configuring these patterns for use with the UI Patterns module felt a little redundant.</p>

<p>In <a href="http://patternlab.io/">Pattern Lab</a> for example you would commonly have a json or yaml file that specified sample data for each of the fields in your pattern. Much of that same data would be once again defined in the yaml file for the related UI Pattern in Drupal. The UI Patterns project has always envisioned that there would eventually be supporting modules that could automatically discover patterns from pattern libraries like Pattern Lab and Fractal, which would make it unnecessary to re-define patterns for use with Drupal. The module even contains classes that could be extended for this purpose. But similar to my initial feelings about the module, that just sounded too good to be true.</p>

<p>I should have seen this coming, but it might not be too good to be true after all.</p>

<p>On an issue in the UI Patterns repository, <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/pdureau">Pierre Dureau</a> shared his work creating such an integration module for use with UI Patterns and Fractal. It made a lot of sense to me when I looked at the code, and seemed like something that would be reasonable to adapt to a Pattern Lab version. I asked around to see if folks would be cool with me taking a shot at that, and the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab">UI Patterns Pattern Lab module</a> was born.</p>

<p>
As of now, UI Patterns Pattern Lab supports the following:
<ul>
<li>Discovering UI Patterns that exist in the templates directory in any module or theme, or any custom twig namespace defined in a theme. Discovered patterns must have a pattern definition file in json or yaml, and a related twig template.</li>
<li>Creating a library that includes css or js assets associated with your pattern.</li>
<li>Parsing documentation from a related pattern documentation markdown file.</li>
<li>Overriding default discovery behavior via variables in the pattern definition file.</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>More detailed documentation is available in <a href="https://www.drupal.org/docs/8/modules/ui-patterns-pattern-lab">the documentation guide on Drupal.org</a></p>

<p>So the call for help part…</p>

<p>I think that the more Pattern Lab instances we can test this against, the more useful it can be (I did some initial testing using Emulsify and was able to fix a handful of bugs as a result.) If you have a Pattern Lab instance that you’d be willing to try with the module (or even just one you’d be willing to share with me), it would be a huge help.</p>

<p>There are a wide variety of ways to configure patterns in Pattern Lab, so don’t be surprised if your pattern library is the one that causes the module to blow up. Also, the thing I’m struggling with right now is how realistic is is to use this with an existing pattern lab instance, especially ones that were set up to do a lot of complicated mapping in twig templates. It remains to be seen if the real use of this module would be with existing pattern lab instance, or along side a pattern library built with this approach in mind. Hopefully after putting this through the paces with a handful of Pattern Lab instances a trend will become obvious.</p>

<p>I’d appreciate any of the help you or your pattern library can lend here. Feel free to get in touch, or <a href="https://github.com/backlineint/ui_patterns_pattern_lab/issues/2">comment on this github issue</a>. Thanks!</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/ui-patterns-pattern-lab-and-a-call-for-help/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/ui-patterns-pattern-lab-and-a-call-for-help/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tldr; I’ve recently been working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab&quot;&gt;UI Patterns Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt; module which automatically discovers components in a Pattern Lab instance for use with Drupal. I’m looking to test it with a variety of Pattern Lab instances - &lt;a href-&quot;https://github.com/backlineint/ui_patterns_pattern_lab/issues/2&quot;&gt;can you help&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we’ve run into each other at Drupal camps over the past couple of years, you’ve probably heard me talk about component based development and most likely also the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns&quot;&gt;UI Patterns Module&lt;/a&gt;. I’m a big supporter of a pattern library driven approach to building a Drupal site, but also feel that some common practices can be complicated - especially for those new to the approach or those not focused on the front end. In my opinion, UI Patterns can reduce that complexity quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the UI Patterns module came along it seemed too good to be true. It allowed patterns to be formally defined as Drupal plugins and took the data mapping that was commonly happening behind the scenes in Twig templates and exposed these in the admin UI where a wider audience could configure and understand them.  But if you were using an external pattern library in your project, configuring these patterns for use with the UI Patterns module felt a little redundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://patternlab.io/&quot;&gt;Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt; for example you would commonly have a json or yaml file that specified sample data for each of the fields in your pattern. Much of that same data would be once again defined in the yaml file for the related UI Pattern in Drupal. The UI Patterns project has always envisioned that there would eventually be supporting modules that could automatically discover patterns from pattern libraries like Pattern Lab and Fractal, which would make it unnecessary to re-define patterns for use with Drupal. The module even contains classes that could be extended for this purpose. But similar to my initial feelings about the module, that just sounded too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should have seen this coming, but it might not be too good to be true after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an issue in the UI Patterns repository, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/pdureau&quot;&gt;Pierre Dureau&lt;/a&gt; shared his work creating such an integration module for use with UI Patterns and Fractal. It made a lot of sense to me when I looked at the code, and seemed like something that would be reasonable to adapt to a Pattern Lab version. I asked around to see if folks would be cool with me taking a shot at that, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_pattern_lab&quot;&gt;UI Patterns Pattern Lab module&lt;/a&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As of now, UI Patterns Pattern Lab supports the following:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovering UI Patterns that exist in the templates directory in any module or theme, or any custom twig namespace defined in a theme. Discovered patterns must have a pattern definition file in json or yaml, and a related twig template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a library that includes css or js assets associated with your pattern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing documentation from a related pattern documentation markdown file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overriding default discovery behavior via variables in the pattern definition file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More detailed documentation is available in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/docs/8/modules/ui-patterns-pattern-lab&quot;&gt;the documentation guide on Drupal.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the call for help part…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the more Pattern Lab instances we can test this against, the more useful it can be (I did some initial testing using Emulsify and was able to fix a handful of bugs as a result.) If you have a Pattern Lab instance that you’d be willing to try with the module (or even just one you’d be willing to share with me), it would be a huge help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a wide variety of ways to configure patterns in Pattern Lab, so don’t be surprised if your pattern library is the one that causes the module to blow up. Also, the thing I’m struggling with right now is how realistic is is to use this with an existing pattern lab instance, especially ones that were set up to do a lot of complicated mapping in twig templates. It remains to be seen if the real use of this module would be with existing pattern lab instance, or along side a pattern library built with this approach in mind. Hopefully after putting this through the paces with a handful of Pattern Lab instances a trend will become obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d appreciate any of the help you or your pattern library can lend here. Feel free to get in touch, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/backlineint/ui_patterns_pattern_lab/issues/2&quot;&gt;comment on this github issue&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In an effort to stay on the absolute cutting edge of web technology, I've added an <a href="http://brianperryinteractive.com/rss.xml">RSS Feed</a>. Enjoy!</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/rss-feed/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/rss-feed/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In an effort to stay on the absolute cutting edge of web technology, I&apos;ve added an &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianperryinteractive.com/rss.xml&quot;&gt;RSS Feed&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chicagoland Half Marathon 2018]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Completed a soaking wet Chicagoland Half Marathon yesterday.  Finished 1:56:49.  About a minute and a half off of my best time, but far from my worst. Hoping for better weather next year.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/chicagoland-half-marathon-2018/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/chicagoland-half-marathon-2018/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Completed a soaking wet Chicagoland Half Marathon yesterday.  Finished 1:56:49.  About a minute and a half off of my best time, but far from my worst. Hoping for better weather next year.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Struggle to Learn React - Brad Frost]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>I’m going to be honest: I’ve had a hell of a time getting my head around React. More than any other technology I’ve touched over the last 10 years of my career, I just haven’t had it click for me. It’s very frustrating as I really want to learn it, and it’s clear the library has legs.</blockquote>

<p>I found React very difficult to learn the first time I attempted it. So much so that I actually just gave up and moved on to other things. Given that, I find Brad's honest take here extremely relatable (except for the part where Dan Abramov personally helped him through his React struggles.) And from a purely selfish perspective, knowing that a developer (sorry, frontend designer) that I admire had similar struggles with React makes me feel a bit better about myself.</p>

<p>I still don't consider myself a React expert, but three specific things made it click for me:</p>

<ul>
<li>I know Brad threw some shade in his post, but <a href="https://reactforbeginners.com/">Wes Bos' React for Beginners</a> just made a lot of sense to me when other tutorials didn't.</li>
<li>I enforced what I learned by applying it to <a href="https://github.com/backlineint/aoty-visualizations">a side project that I found legitimately interesting</a>.</li>
<li>I eventually realized that I was trying to tackle things that were too complex. It wasn't until I focused on nailing some really basic stuff that things started to move fast and click. For me it was representing data in a table before I started trying to filter, sort, or otherwise visualize that data. For Brad it was <a href="http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/dumb-react/">rendering a full page worth of mock components</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>I'm glad I pushed through. Even though I have a lot to learn and a limited amount of time to do so, I really like React.</p> ]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/my-struggle-to-learn-react-brad-frost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/my-struggle-to-learn-react-brad-frost/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;I’m going to be honest: I’ve had a hell of a time getting my head around React. More than any other technology I’ve touched over the last 10 years of my career, I just haven’t had it click for me. It’s very frustrating as I really want to learn it, and it’s clear the library has legs.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found React very difficult to learn the first time I attempted it. So much so that I actually just gave up and moved on to other things. Given that, I find Brad&apos;s honest take here extremely relatable (except for the part where Dan Abramov personally helped him through his React struggles.) And from a purely selfish perspective, knowing that a developer (sorry, frontend designer) that I admire had similar struggles with React makes me feel a bit better about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don&apos;t consider myself a React expert, but three specific things made it click for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know Brad threw some shade in his post, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactforbeginners.com/&quot;&gt;Wes Bos&apos; React for Beginners&lt;/a&gt; just made a lot of sense to me when other tutorials didn&apos;t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enforced what I learned by applying it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/backlineint/aoty-visualizations&quot;&gt;a side project that I found legitimately interesting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I eventually realized that I was trying to tackle things that were too complex. It wasn&apos;t until I focused on nailing some really basic stuff that things started to move fast and click. For me it was representing data in a table before I started trying to filter, sort, or otherwise visualize that data. For Brad it was &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradfrost.com/blog/post/dumb-react/&quot;&gt;rendering a full page worth of mock components&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m glad I pushed through. Even though I have a lot to learn and a limited amount of time to do so, I really like React.&lt;/p&gt; </content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Recommended Pattern Lab Version and Edition for Drupal Integration]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Saw some useful clarification in the #pattern-lab channel on the <a href="http://drupaltwig-slack.herokuapp.com/">Drupaltwig slack</a> about which version and edition of Pattern Lab is recommended to use with Drupal going forward.</p>

<ul>
<li>As far as which repository to use,  <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/evanlovely">EvanLovely</a> and <a href="https://github.com/sghoweri">Salem Ghoweri</a> clarified that we should be using the main Pattern Lab repository, not the Drupal fork that was previously active. Most if not all of the changes from the fork have been merged back into the main Pattern Lab repository.</li>
<li>And regarding the edition, <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/evanlovely">EvanLovely</a> somewhat surprisingly recommends the Twig edition over the Drupal edition. Apparently the differences are minimal, and "A true Drupal edition is better represented as a Drupal theme with the Twig edition integrated."</li>
</ul>

<p>So in summary, the next time you need Pattern Lab for a Drupal project, <a href="https://github.com/pattern-lab/edition-php-twig-standard">go here</a>.</p> 

<p>Helpful clarification given all of the Pattern Lab forks and editions floating around out there.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/recommended-pattern-lab-version-and-edition-for-drupal-integration/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/recommended-pattern-lab-version-and-edition-for-drupal-integration/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Saw some useful clarification in the #pattern-lab channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupaltwig-slack.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;Drupaltwig slack&lt;/a&gt; about which version and edition of Pattern Lab is recommended to use with Drupal going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As far as which repository to use,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/evanlovely&quot;&gt;EvanLovely&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sghoweri&quot;&gt;Salem Ghoweri&lt;/a&gt; clarified that we should be using the main Pattern Lab repository, not the Drupal fork that was previously active. Most if not all of the changes from the fork have been merged back into the main Pattern Lab repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And regarding the edition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/evanlovely&quot;&gt;EvanLovely&lt;/a&gt; somewhat surprisingly recommends the Twig edition over the Drupal edition. Apparently the differences are minimal, and &quot;A true Drupal edition is better represented as a Drupal theme with the Twig edition integrated.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in summary, the next time you need Pattern Lab for a Drupal project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pattern-lab/edition-php-twig-standard&quot;&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Helpful clarification given all of the Pattern Lab forks and editions floating around out there.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Re-Retirement From Comedy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>If the photo above of me forcing Evan to perform much of the show as a talking broom didn't make it clear, being back at ImprovBoston for the 10th anniversary of Harold Night was a blast. It was strange being back in the building at first, but once I set foot on stage it felt as if no time had passed at all. And I even had an opportunity to publicly shame my brother for his eating habits, which makes the night a success by any measure.</p> 
<p>Thanks to all who took in this over the top show, avoided my flailing limbs when I repeatedly climbed over audience chairs, and humored a now dad-heavy group of improvisers as they gave comedy one more spin. Being able to see so many great friends that I hadn't seen in years makes getting stuck on the red line for an hour more than worth it.</p>
<p>The show was such a success that I'll once again be retiring from improv effective immediately. I'll see you all at the 20 year reunion.</p>
<p>(Photo via <a href="https://twitter.com/haroldnight">@haroldnight</a>. Another <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/haroldnight/photos/?tab=album&album_id=10156702164471535">great photo set</a> is available on the Harold Night Facebook page.)</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/my-re-retirement-from-comedy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/my-re-retirement-from-comedy/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If the photo above of me forcing Evan to perform much of the show as a talking broom didn&apos;t make it clear, being back at ImprovBoston for the 10th anniversary of Harold Night was a blast. It was strange being back in the building at first, but once I set foot on stage it felt as if no time had passed at all. And I even had an opportunity to publicly shame my brother for his eating habits, which makes the night a success by any measure.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all who took in this over the top show, avoided my flailing limbs when I repeatedly climbed over audience chairs, and humored a now dad-heavy group of improvisers as they gave comedy one more spin. Being able to see so many great friends that I hadn&apos;t seen in years makes getting stuck on the red line for an hour more than worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show was such a success that I&apos;ll once again be retiring from improv effective immediately. I&apos;ll see you all at the 20 year reunion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Photo via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/haroldnight&quot;&gt;@haroldnight&lt;/a&gt;. Another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/haroldnight/photos/?tab=album&amp;album_id=10156702164471535&quot;&gt;great photo set&lt;/a&gt; is available on the Harold Night Facebook page.)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Brief Unretirement From Comedy]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hard to believe, but it has been years since I've been on stage doing anything resembling improv. I would have guessed that my comedy days were over for good. Well, they still are! But for one night I'm getting back on stage with some old friends at my old stomping grounds to improvise like it was 2008. Will we change the face of comedy forever?  Will we mostly talk about our kids while hanging out in the green room? Will we even be able to stay awake past 10:30 PM? <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/hnx-harold-night-celebrates-ten-years-tickets-45323998299">Join us</a> on Wednesday May 2, 2018 to find out.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/my-brief-unretirement-from-comedy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/my-brief-unretirement-from-comedy/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hard to believe, but it has been years since I&apos;ve been on stage doing anything resembling improv. I would have guessed that my comedy days were over for good. Well, they still are! But for one night I&apos;m getting back on stage with some old friends at my old stomping grounds to improvise like it was 2008. Will we change the face of comedy forever?  Will we mostly talk about our kids while hanging out in the green room? Will we even be able to stay awake past 10:30 PM? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/hnx-harold-night-celebrates-ten-years-tickets-45323998299&quot;&gt;Join us&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday May 2, 2018 to find out.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Takeaways from DrupalCon Nashville]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m more than a little late on the traditional DrupalCon recap this year, but even with some time between me and Nashville what I took away is still quite vivid. Better get it in writing before the remaining echoes of country music drown it out.</p>

<p>My most important takeaway from my trip was that the Nashville Predators let fans smash a car painted with the opponents logo before games. Beyond that, I did also learn some things while at DrupalCon.</p>

<p><b>There is a lot of excitement behind Layout Builder and layout related initiatives</b></p>

<p>What the Layout Initiative was able to accomplish with the release of Layout Builder as an experimental module in Drupal 8.5 was extremely impressive.  It is a great foundation that the initiative already appears to have clear plans to flesh out and improve.  It was promising to see many well attended sessions on this topic, coverage in the <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/driesnote">Driesnote</a>, and quite a bit of excitement about layouts and Layout Builder buzzing through the halls of Music City Center.</p>

<p>The biggest gap I see in what exists thus far is the disconnect between the block based layout builder and the blocks UI. You currently have to leave the layout builder interface to create new custom blocks before you can add them to a layout, and these blocks have the potential to flood the main Drupal custom blocks UI.  I was very happy to hear that there is <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/drupal/issues/2948064">an issue related to inline creation of custom blocks</a> that should help bridge this gap. In a BOF on Components and The Layout Initiative <a href="http://bit.ly/components-layout">a number of other relevant issues were identified</a> that could potentially improve the experience and make Layout Builder play even more nicely with component based workflows. I’m hoping to follow along with these, go hands on frequently, and help out where I can.</p>

<p><b>Many are decoupling, but approaches vary</b><p>

<p>To poorly paraphrase <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/mrjmd">Matt Davis</a>:</p>

<blockquote>Many people build websites this way outside of the Drupal world, they just don’t call it decoupled</blockquote>

<p>There was a lot of great discussion at the Decoupled Summit (<a href="https://www.lullabot.com/articles/decoupled-drupal-summit-at-drupalcon">Lullabot has a good recap</a>) but also a feeling that while decoupling continues to gain momentum in the Drupal community, there are still a wide variety of strategies and some alignment on best practices yet to come. That said, I think some of that feeling may just come with the territory of the flexibility of an API based approach and the wide array of application frameworks that can consume these APIs.</p>

<p>An interesting topic that came up was the concept of content preview and managing editorial layouts. In the developer case studies portion of the summit we saw a number of attempted solutions to these problems, including an amazing offering from <a href="http://www.1xinternet.de/">1XInternet</a> that allowed content managed in Drupal to be edited in either the Drupal or React UI with updates syndicated in near real time. Wow factor aside, conversations later in the summit brought that entire approach into question. The counterpoint being that these editorial conveniences are page-centric in nature and thus won’t always make sense in a truly decoupled context. In this case we’re either putting in a large amount of effort to replicate the traditional coupled website editing experience, or this only represents one portion of the editorial experience we’re trying to manage.  It is understandable that we’re often falling back to the page centric approaches we’re familiar with, but this is more evidence that our approaches to decoupling are still maturing.</p>

<p>Discussions during the summit also often crossed into two key initiatives...</p>

<p><b>The Drupal community is pushing to modernize...</b></p>

<p><a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/drupal/issues/2926656">The Javascript Modernization Initiative</a> looks to improve Drupal’s JavaScript by improving the experience of maintaining Drupal’s current JavaScript codebase, and also creating <a href="https://github.com/jsdrupal/drupal-admin-ui-demo">a new alternative admin UI for Drupal based in React</a>. The initiative has already introduced the AirBnB standards and a JavaScript build process to Drupal Core, but there are more welcome changes on the horizon. One focus area is improving Drupal’s JavaScript based test suite by phasing out the use of PhantomJS and transitioning to Nightwatch.js. They are also attempting to manage aspects of the project primarily on Github which I’d imagine would be a welcome change for many JavaScript developers.</p>

<p>Another common theme that kept coming up is that the JS initiative has a small group working on these issues and could really use additional help. This is another area where I’d love to find a way to contribute in the coming months.</p>

<p>In addition to serving as a proof of concept for how Drupal might utilize React, this UI also crosses over nicely with <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ideas/issues/2757967">the API-first initiative</a> since the alternative admin UI that is being developed depends on Drupal’s API.  The API-first initiative aims to advance Drupal’s web services in support of decoupling and other new types of integration. Closing gaps in Drupal’s API (file upload support was one that came up as a high priority for 8.6) that could support a decoupled admin UI would also make Drupal’s API more suitable for consumers outside of core.</p>

<p><b>…but there could be more alignment on how we’re approaching modernization</b><p>

<p>Complete with its admittedly clickbait title, core conversation <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/farewell-twig">A Farewell to Twig</a> received the passionate discussion that the session appeared to be aiming for. This early and theoretical discussion focused on the concept of making client rendering a first class citizen in Drupal and potentially focusing more on decoupling rather than solving all aspects of front end development. One possible approach involved enhancing Drupal’s front end to be decoupled out of the box and then offering one or more decoupled front ends that could optionally be used with Drupal.  There were various theories on how far this would go - from shipping with a Twig front end by default (a common concern from the audience was related to continuing to support Twig for small to mid range projects, and also for general consistency) all the way to the concept of not shipping with a front end by default.</p>

<p>It was a thought provoking discussion that also sparked some dissonance with the other things I’d been hearing and thinking about throughout the conference. Much of Dries’ focus in his keynote was on improving the content creator and site builder experience, along with promoting Drupal to non-technical decision makers. This aligns nicely with the layout work (which also featured prominently in the keynote,) but it feels at odds with the focus within the community on decoupling. Can both directions be correct?  Should both efforts be happening in parallel? Should I just relax and enjoy all of the new functionality and improvements Drupal has to offer? No easy answers here, so <a href="https://fulldegreeheyyouau.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/why-not-both-animated-gif-7.gif?w=748">I’ll just link to a relevant meme</a>.</p>

<p>Tangentially related, <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/stevector">Steve Persch</a> talked about Drupal’s mission statement compared to WordPress' during the <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/whats-possible-wordpress-50">What's possible with WordPress 5.0</a> presentation. Those missions are best summarized as:</p>

<p>Wordpress: Democratize publishing<br />
Drupal: Ambitious Digital Experiences</p>

<p>I’d agree that Drupal’s mission statement isn’t as easy to hang your hat on when compared to WordPress. And does ‘Ambitious Digital Experiences’ really represent what was focused on during the Driesnote?  I’m not so sure.</p>

<p><b>Presenting at DrupalCon was a ton of fun</b><p>

<p>I also had the pleasure of presenting <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React</a>. This was my first time speaking at DrupalCon and I had a ton of fun doing so.</p> 

<p>Probably my most interesting takeaway from the session was from an informal poll before the recording even started. The vast majority of people in the room either identified as being new to decoupled Drupal, or new to React. In fact, the vast majority was new to both. This seems to confirm my working theory that there are a lot of people interested in decoupled concepts in the Drupal community but are struggling to find a way to get started. I hope this talk provided a decent starting point and inspired some people to dive in and start experimenting.</p>

<p>Thanks to everyone who attended, packed the room, and provided thoughts and feedback.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d0HOsc5nQtM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p><b>This was my most social sprint experience</b></p>

<p>This DrupalCon sprint was different for me in that I spent the majority of my time having some great conversations rather than actively writing code. I finally had a chance to meet <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/kclarkson">Kaleem Clarkson</a> face to face and talk about how he’s been using the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/foundation_patterns">Foundation Patterns theme</a>. I also got to meet and have a nice conversation with <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/murrayw">Murray Woodman</a> talking to him a bit about how I’ve been using the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns">UI Patterns</a> module, along with his work with <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/bricks">Bricks</a> and <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/modifiers">Modifiers</a>. Especially interesting as earlier in the week I had been talking with <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/scott-weston">Scott at HS2</a> about how he’s been using the Modifiers module.</p>

<p>And I got lunch at <a href="https://www.martinsbbqjoint.com/">the best BBQ place in Nashville</a> (according to one of my many Lyft drivers anyway.)</p>

<p><b>Kevin!</b></p>

<p>It was a damn pleasure to be there in person to see <a href="https://www.drupal.org/forum/general/community-spotlight/2018-04-24/kevin-thull-from-behind-the-camera">Kevin Thull accept the Aaron Winborn award</a></p>

<p><b>Looking forward to continuing the momentum</b></p>

<p>As always, DrupalCon has me energized and ready to run with this Drupal related excitement (although not enough to get this post out quickly for some reason.)  I hope to continue speaking at camps, find some ways to contribute to the initiatives that took up most of my focus at DrupalCon, and an episode of the <a href="http://www.developingup.com/">Developing Up podcast</a> that I recorded with <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/mikemiles86">Mike Miles</a> at DrupalCon will be released sometime in the future as well.</p>

<p><b>Other Great Sessions:</b>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/advanced-configuration-management-drupal-8">Advanced Configuration Management in Drupal 8</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/keynote-drupal-and-secret-my-success">Keynote: Drupal and the secret of my success | Steve Francia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/site-building-20-how-layout-builder-will-change-everything">Site Building 2.0: How Layout Builder will change everything</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/intro-react-design-patterns">Introduction to React Design Patterns</a></li>
</ul></p>

<p><b>Sessions I’m Still Hoping to Watch:</b>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/build-banging-sites-bpm-bricks-paragraphs-and-modifiers">Build banging sites with BPM: Bricks, Paragraphs and Modifiers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/advanced-topics-decoupled-drupal">Advanced topics in decoupled Drupal</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/next-level-twig-extensions">Next Level Twig: Extensions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/shifting-ux-editorial-experience-0">Shifting UX to the Editorial Experience</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/javascript-and-accessibility-dont-blame-language">JavaScript and Accessibility: Don't Blame the Language</a></li>
<li><a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/weathercoms-project-moonracer-decoupled-user-interfaces">Weather.com's Project Moonracer - Decoupled User Interfaces</a></li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>See you in Seattle!</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/my-takeaways-from-drupalcon-nashville/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/my-takeaways-from-drupalcon-nashville/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m more than a little late on the traditional DrupalCon recap this year, but even with some time between me and Nashville what I took away is still quite vivid. Better get it in writing before the remaining echoes of country music drown it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most important takeaway from my trip was that the Nashville Predators let fans smash a car painted with the opponents logo before games. Beyond that, I did also learn some things while at DrupalCon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;There is a lot of excitement behind Layout Builder and layout related initiatives&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the Layout Initiative was able to accomplish with the release of Layout Builder as an experimental module in Drupal 8.5 was extremely impressive.  It is a great foundation that the initiative already appears to have clear plans to flesh out and improve.  It was promising to see many well attended sessions on this topic, coverage in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/driesnote&quot;&gt;Driesnote&lt;/a&gt;, and quite a bit of excitement about layouts and Layout Builder buzzing through the halls of Music City Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest gap I see in what exists thus far is the disconnect between the block based layout builder and the blocks UI. You currently have to leave the layout builder interface to create new custom blocks before you can add them to a layout, and these blocks have the potential to flood the main Drupal custom blocks UI.  I was very happy to hear that there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/drupal/issues/2948064&quot;&gt;an issue related to inline creation of custom blocks&lt;/a&gt; that should help bridge this gap. In a BOF on Components and The Layout Initiative &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/components-layout&quot;&gt;a number of other relevant issues were identified&lt;/a&gt; that could potentially improve the experience and make Layout Builder play even more nicely with component based workflows. I’m hoping to follow along with these, go hands on frequently, and help out where I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Many are decoupling, but approaches vary&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To poorly paraphrase &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/mrjmd&quot;&gt;Matt Davis&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Many people build websites this way outside of the Drupal world, they just don’t call it decoupled&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of great discussion at the Decoupled Summit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lullabot.com/articles/decoupled-drupal-summit-at-drupalcon&quot;&gt;Lullabot has a good recap&lt;/a&gt;) but also a feeling that while decoupling continues to gain momentum in the Drupal community, there are still a wide variety of strategies and some alignment on best practices yet to come. That said, I think some of that feeling may just come with the territory of the flexibility of an API based approach and the wide array of application frameworks that can consume these APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting topic that came up was the concept of content preview and managing editorial layouts. In the developer case studies portion of the summit we saw a number of attempted solutions to these problems, including an amazing offering from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1xinternet.de/&quot;&gt;1XInternet&lt;/a&gt; that allowed content managed in Drupal to be edited in either the Drupal or React UI with updates syndicated in near real time. Wow factor aside, conversations later in the summit brought that entire approach into question. The counterpoint being that these editorial conveniences are page-centric in nature and thus won’t always make sense in a truly decoupled context. In this case we’re either putting in a large amount of effort to replicate the traditional coupled website editing experience, or this only represents one portion of the editorial experience we’re trying to manage.  It is understandable that we’re often falling back to the page centric approaches we’re familiar with, but this is more evidence that our approaches to decoupling are still maturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussions during the summit also often crossed into two key initiatives...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Drupal community is pushing to modernize...&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/drupal/issues/2926656&quot;&gt;The Javascript Modernization Initiative&lt;/a&gt; looks to improve Drupal’s JavaScript by improving the experience of maintaining Drupal’s current JavaScript codebase, and also creating &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jsdrupal/drupal-admin-ui-demo&quot;&gt;a new alternative admin UI for Drupal based in React&lt;/a&gt;. The initiative has already introduced the AirBnB standards and a JavaScript build process to Drupal Core, but there are more welcome changes on the horizon. One focus area is improving Drupal’s JavaScript based test suite by phasing out the use of PhantomJS and transitioning to Nightwatch.js. They are also attempting to manage aspects of the project primarily on Github which I’d imagine would be a welcome change for many JavaScript developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common theme that kept coming up is that the JS initiative has a small group working on these issues and could really use additional help. This is another area where I’d love to find a way to contribute in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to serving as a proof of concept for how Drupal might utilize React, this UI also crosses over nicely with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ideas/issues/2757967&quot;&gt;the API-first initiative&lt;/a&gt; since the alternative admin UI that is being developed depends on Drupal’s API.  The API-first initiative aims to advance Drupal’s web services in support of decoupling and other new types of integration. Closing gaps in Drupal’s API (file upload support was one that came up as a high priority for 8.6) that could support a decoupled admin UI would also make Drupal’s API more suitable for consumers outside of core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;…but there could be more alignment on how we’re approaching modernization&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete with its admittedly clickbait title, core conversation &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/farewell-twig&quot;&gt;A Farewell to Twig&lt;/a&gt; received the passionate discussion that the session appeared to be aiming for. This early and theoretical discussion focused on the concept of making client rendering a first class citizen in Drupal and potentially focusing more on decoupling rather than solving all aspects of front end development. One possible approach involved enhancing Drupal’s front end to be decoupled out of the box and then offering one or more decoupled front ends that could optionally be used with Drupal.  There were various theories on how far this would go - from shipping with a Twig front end by default (a common concern from the audience was related to continuing to support Twig for small to mid range projects, and also for general consistency) all the way to the concept of not shipping with a front end by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a thought provoking discussion that also sparked some dissonance with the other things I’d been hearing and thinking about throughout the conference. Much of Dries’ focus in his keynote was on improving the content creator and site builder experience, along with promoting Drupal to non-technical decision makers. This aligns nicely with the layout work (which also featured prominently in the keynote,) but it feels at odds with the focus within the community on decoupling. Can both directions be correct?  Should both efforts be happening in parallel? Should I just relax and enjoy all of the new functionality and improvements Drupal has to offer? No easy answers here, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://fulldegreeheyyouau.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/why-not-both-animated-gif-7.gif?w=748&quot;&gt;I’ll just link to a relevant meme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tangentially related, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/stevector&quot;&gt;Steve Persch&lt;/a&gt; talked about Drupal’s mission statement compared to WordPress&apos; during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/whats-possible-wordpress-50&quot;&gt;What&apos;s possible with WordPress 5.0&lt;/a&gt; presentation. Those missions are best summarized as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress: Democratize publishing&lt;br /&gt;
Drupal: Ambitious Digital Experiences&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d agree that Drupal’s mission statement isn’t as easy to hang your hat on when compared to WordPress. And does ‘Ambitious Digital Experiences’ really represent what was focused on during the Driesnote?  I’m not so sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presenting at DrupalCon was a ton of fun&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had the pleasure of presenting &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React&lt;/a&gt;. This was my first time speaking at DrupalCon and I had a ton of fun doing so.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Probably my most interesting takeaway from the session was from an informal poll before the recording even started. The vast majority of people in the room either identified as being new to decoupled Drupal, or new to React. In fact, the vast majority was new to both. This seems to confirm my working theory that there are a lot of people interested in decoupled concepts in the Drupal community but are struggling to find a way to get started. I hope this talk provided a decent starting point and inspired some people to dive in and start experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who attended, packed the room, and provided thoughts and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/d0HOsc5nQtM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This was my most social sprint experience&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This DrupalCon sprint was different for me in that I spent the majority of my time having some great conversations rather than actively writing code. I finally had a chance to meet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/kclarkson&quot;&gt;Kaleem Clarkson&lt;/a&gt; face to face and talk about how he’s been using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/foundation_patterns&quot;&gt;Foundation Patterns theme&lt;/a&gt;. I also got to meet and have a nice conversation with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/murrayw&quot;&gt;Murray Woodman&lt;/a&gt; talking to him a bit about how I’ve been using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns&quot;&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; module, along with his work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/bricks&quot;&gt;Bricks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/modifiers&quot;&gt;Modifiers&lt;/a&gt;. Especially interesting as earlier in the week I had been talking with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/scott-weston&quot;&gt;Scott at HS2&lt;/a&gt; about how he’s been using the Modifiers module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I got lunch at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.martinsbbqjoint.com/&quot;&gt;the best BBQ place in Nashville&lt;/a&gt; (according to one of my many Lyft drivers anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kevin!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a damn pleasure to be there in person to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/forum/general/community-spotlight/2018-04-24/kevin-thull-from-behind-the-camera&quot;&gt;Kevin Thull accept the Aaron Winborn award&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Looking forward to continuing the momentum&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, DrupalCon has me energized and ready to run with this Drupal related excitement (although not enough to get this post out quickly for some reason.)  I hope to continue speaking at camps, find some ways to contribute to the initiatives that took up most of my focus at DrupalCon, and an episode of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.developingup.com/&quot;&gt;Developing Up podcast&lt;/a&gt; that I recorded with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/mikemiles86&quot;&gt;Mike Miles&lt;/a&gt; at DrupalCon will be released sometime in the future as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other Great Sessions:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/advanced-configuration-management-drupal-8&quot;&gt;Advanced Configuration Management in Drupal 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/keynote-drupal-and-secret-my-success&quot;&gt;Keynote: Drupal and the secret of my success | Steve Francia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/site-building-20-how-layout-builder-will-change-everything&quot;&gt;Site Building 2.0: How Layout Builder will change everything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/intro-react-design-patterns&quot;&gt;Introduction to React Design Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sessions I’m Still Hoping to Watch:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/build-banging-sites-bpm-bricks-paragraphs-and-modifiers&quot;&gt;Build banging sites with BPM: Bricks, Paragraphs and Modifiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/advanced-topics-decoupled-drupal&quot;&gt;Advanced topics in decoupled Drupal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/next-level-twig-extensions&quot;&gt;Next Level Twig: Extensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/shifting-ux-editorial-experience-0&quot;&gt;Shifting UX to the Editorial Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/javascript-and-accessibility-dont-blame-language&quot;&gt;JavaScript and Accessibility: Don&apos;t Blame the Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/weathercoms-project-moonracer-decoupled-user-interfaces&quot;&gt;Weather.com&apos;s Project Moonracer - Decoupled User Interfaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you in Seattle!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[DrupalCon Nashville in a Photo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This pretty much sums up my DrupalCon Nashville experience.  Thanks to Chris Greatens for the goofy photo.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/drupalcon-nashville-in-a-photo/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/drupalcon-nashville-in-a-photo/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This pretty much sums up my DrupalCon Nashville experience.  Thanks to Chris Greatens for the goofy photo.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Looking Forward to DrupalCon Nashville]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Very much looking forward to spending next week in Nashville attending my 4th <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018">DrupalCon</a>. The spontaneous and unplanned stuff is half of the fun, but there are a few things that are locked on my schedule.</p>
<p><b>Monday: <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/decoupled-summit">Decoupled Summit</a></b> - I'm excited to hear more about what people are doing in the decoupled Drupal space. This will be my first time attending a summit at DrupalCon as well.</p>
<p><b>Tuesday 1 PM: <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/bofs/components-and-layout-initiative">Components and the Layout Initiative BOF</a></b> - I'll be leading an open discussion on how the Layout Initiative might impact our component-based workflows. I've really enjoyed the BOFs I've led in the past and expect this to be no exception.</p>
<p><b>Wednesday 3:45 PM: <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React</a></b> - I'll be sharing my experience building a music discovery app with Drupal and React in my first ever talk at DrupalCon.</p>
<p><b>Thursday: Who knows!</b></p>
<p><b>Friday: <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sprints">Sprints</a></b> - after a week of exciting new ideas, having a sprint to go hands on is a great way to end the week.  I plan on getting back to some forward progress on the <a href="https://github.com/backlineint/foundation_patterns">Foundation Patterns</a> theme.</p>
<p>Can't wait to say see friends old and new, learn a bunch of cool new stuff, and land a country music recording contract.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/looking-forward-to-drupalcon-nashville/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/looking-forward-to-drupalcon-nashville/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Very much looking forward to spending next week in Nashville attending my 4th &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018&quot;&gt;DrupalCon&lt;/a&gt;. The spontaneous and unplanned stuff is half of the fun, but there are a few things that are locked on my schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Monday: &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/decoupled-summit&quot;&gt;Decoupled Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - I&apos;m excited to hear more about what people are doing in the decoupled Drupal space. This will be my first time attending a summit at DrupalCon as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tuesday 1 PM: &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/bofs/components-and-layout-initiative&quot;&gt;Components and the Layout Initiative BOF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - I&apos;ll be leading an open discussion on how the Layout Initiative might impact our component-based workflows. I&apos;ve really enjoyed the BOFs I&apos;ve led in the past and expect this to be no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wednesday 3:45 PM: &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;Hot JAMS(tack): Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - I&apos;ll be sharing my experience building a music discovery app with Drupal and React in my first ever talk at DrupalCon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thursday: Who knows!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Friday: &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sprints&quot;&gt;Sprints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - after a week of exciting new ideas, having a sprint to go hands on is a great way to end the week.  I plan on getting back to some forward progress on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/backlineint/foundation_patterns&quot;&gt;Foundation Patterns&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can&apos;t wait to say see friends old and new, learn a bunch of cool new stuff, and land a country music recording contract.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Drupal 8.5 and Security Updates]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As always, I learned a few things this week upgrading projects to Drupal 8.5 and applying the most recent <a href="https://www.drupal.org/sa-core-2018-002">highly critical Drupal security update</a>.</p>

<p>The first is yet another reminder to carefully read and consider the documentation. The highest priority projects that I needed to apply the security release to were on 8.4.5 at the time of the pre-announcement. I took this as a good opportunity to upgrade to 8.5 and then kind of got tunnel vision about getting these projects, and also my lower priority D8 projects up to 8.5 in preparation for the security release. Not having looked back at the security advisory since my initial read, I lost sight of the fact that I could easily apply the patch to their current D8 version and worry about 8.5 when the pressure was off a little bit.  Thankfully I was reminded of this during a well timed check in meeting with the Drupal practice at HS2 - a few of my 8.5 upgrades were a little behind schedule.  Having the flexibility to apply the security update to older versions of D8 really helped and most likely prevented us from rushing a few upgrade related regressions out into production.</p>

<p>Speaking of the 8.5 upgrade getting a bit behind schedule, minor Drupal updates (8.4, 8.5 and so on) are still more challenging than I'd expect them to be.  Jeff Geerling's post <a href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2018/updating-drupalcore-composer-drupal-core-doesnt-update">Updating drupal/core with Composer - but Drupal core doesn't update</a> proved invaluable as I ran into the same issue. I also had another pretty tricky dependency conflict that eventually required me to remove and work around a dependency (again, <a href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2018/updating-drupalcore-composer-drupal-core-doesnt-update">Jeff Geerling's post</a> helped quite a bit here.)  After successfully upgrading to 8.5 composer-wise, I found that <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/page_manager/issues/2918564">a patch to Page Manager</a> needed to be applied for the site to even run.</p>

<p>I'm getting better with managing Drupal projects via composer, but still have some room to grow.  Lowest hanging fruit is that I need to start managing patches via composer. Once that clicked in my brain it was a little to late to experiment with it.  Next time.  I also still sometimes get tripped up with the difference between the ^ and ~ version constraints in composer.json which is embarrassing to admit.</p>

<p>I also ran updates on Drupal instances based on API-first distributions. Those were a bit of a different beast. In my case, most were single purpose enough that I was able to just run composer update and call it a day.  That said, each distro had their quirks.  The version of <a href="https://github.com/acquia/reservoir">Reservoir</a> I was using had a dependency conflict that prevented the upgrade until I manually locked Reservoir at Alpha 4. <a href="http://www.contentacms.org/">Contenta</a> seems to have <a href="https://github.com/contentacms/contenta_jsonapi/issues/266">a patch that won't apply to 8.5</a></p>

<p>I'm all for learning, but also looking forward to this process becoming smoother sailing in the future.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/drupal-8.5-and-security-updates/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/drupal-8.5-and-security-updates/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As always, I learned a few things this week upgrading projects to Drupal 8.5 and applying the most recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/sa-core-2018-002&quot;&gt;highly critical Drupal security update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is yet another reminder to carefully read and consider the documentation. The highest priority projects that I needed to apply the security release to were on 8.4.5 at the time of the pre-announcement. I took this as a good opportunity to upgrade to 8.5 and then kind of got tunnel vision about getting these projects, and also my lower priority D8 projects up to 8.5 in preparation for the security release. Not having looked back at the security advisory since my initial read, I lost sight of the fact that I could easily apply the patch to their current D8 version and worry about 8.5 when the pressure was off a little bit.  Thankfully I was reminded of this during a well timed check in meeting with the Drupal practice at HS2 - a few of my 8.5 upgrades were a little behind schedule.  Having the flexibility to apply the security update to older versions of D8 really helped and most likely prevented us from rushing a few upgrade related regressions out into production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the 8.5 upgrade getting a bit behind schedule, minor Drupal updates (8.4, 8.5 and so on) are still more challenging than I&apos;d expect them to be.  Jeff Geerling&apos;s post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2018/updating-drupalcore-composer-drupal-core-doesnt-update&quot;&gt;Updating drupal/core with Composer - but Drupal core doesn&apos;t update&lt;/a&gt; proved invaluable as I ran into the same issue. I also had another pretty tricky dependency conflict that eventually required me to remove and work around a dependency (again, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2018/updating-drupalcore-composer-drupal-core-doesnt-update&quot;&gt;Jeff Geerling&apos;s post&lt;/a&gt; helped quite a bit here.)  After successfully upgrading to 8.5 composer-wise, I found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/page_manager/issues/2918564&quot;&gt;a patch to Page Manager&lt;/a&gt; needed to be applied for the site to even run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m getting better with managing Drupal projects via composer, but still have some room to grow.  Lowest hanging fruit is that I need to start managing patches via composer. Once that clicked in my brain it was a little to late to experiment with it.  Next time.  I also still sometimes get tripped up with the difference between the ^ and ~ version constraints in composer.json which is embarrassing to admit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also ran updates on Drupal instances based on API-first distributions. Those were a bit of a different beast. In my case, most were single purpose enough that I was able to just run composer update and call it a day.  That said, each distro had their quirks.  The version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/acquia/reservoir&quot;&gt;Reservoir&lt;/a&gt; I was using had a dependency conflict that prevented the upgrade until I manually locked Reservoir at Alpha 4. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.contentacms.org/&quot;&gt;Contenta&lt;/a&gt; seems to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/contentacms/contenta_jsonapi/issues/266&quot;&gt;a patch that won&apos;t apply to 8.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m all for learning, but also looking forward to this process becoming smoother sailing in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shop Talk Show 303: JAM Stack with Phil Hawksworth]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A great listen that could serve as a solid introduction to the JAM Stack concept. Especially interesting was the focus on some common counter arguments to the JAM Stack (dynamic things like forms, comments and so on) and how those may be more achievable than one might originally assume. As I try to add a little more punch to the JAM Stack focused portion of <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">my DrupalCon talk</a> I see myself going back for another listen.</p>
<p>With a <a href="https://www.drupal.org/psa-2018-001">new critical Drupal security release</a> on the horizon, static site builds are looking better and better. I'm glad I won't have to won't have to worry about this site (Drupal isn't accessible to the public) while I scramble to apply the security release elsewhere.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/shop-talk-show-303:-jam-stack-with-phil-hawksworth/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/shop-talk-show-303:-jam-stack-with-phil-hawksworth/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A great listen that could serve as a solid introduction to the JAM Stack concept. Especially interesting was the focus on some common counter arguments to the JAM Stack (dynamic things like forms, comments and so on) and how those may be more achievable than one might originally assume. As I try to add a little more punch to the JAM Stack focused portion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;my DrupalCon talk&lt;/a&gt; I see myself going back for another listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/psa-2018-001&quot;&gt;new critical Drupal security release&lt;/a&gt; on the horizon, static site builds are looking better and better. I&apos;m glad I won&apos;t have to won&apos;t have to worry about this site (Drupal isn&apos;t accessible to the public) while I scramble to apply the security release elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[MidCamp 2018 Thoughts]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Another year, another great MidCamp!</p>

<p>I wasn’t able to attend for training and sprints on Thursday (1st grade play FTW!) but ended up talking to a former co-worker who attended the training '<a href="https://www.midcamp.org/training/what-am-i-getting-myself-drupal-crash-course-non-developers">What Am I Getting Myself Into? A Drupal Crash Course for Non-Developers.</a>’ While it's easy to get wrapped up in the new and advanced at a camp like this, it is also really important to see newcomers, beginners, and people with Drupal-adjacent roles take steps into becoming more hands on with the CMS. She specifically mentioned that the training helped her have some revelations about a few Drupal-isms that us crazy developers have been talking about all this time.</p>

<p>After some really enjoyable traffic, Friday brought me to the first day of sessions.  A couple of highlights:</p>

<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/local-dev-environments-dummies">Local Dev Environments for Dummies</a> - the bulk of this presentation reviewed data from a 2018 Drupal Developer Survey, and the data alone was extremely fascinating. It also provided some interesting perspectives on Vagrant vs. Docker for local development (go Vagrant if matching your prod environment exactly is important, and Docker for pretty much everything else.) I also walked out of this one itching to learn more about <a href="https://docs.devwithlando.io/">Lando</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/decoupled-drupal-across-stack">Decoupled Drupal Across The Stack</a> - always enjoy seeing <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/prestonso">Preston</a> speak about Decoupled Drupal, and being aware of his (and Acquia’s) perspective on the topic is important if I’m going to be speaking about adjacent topics as well. A good talk for  someone looking to survey the current Decoupled Drupal landscape. Was interesting to see that all of the examples Preston provided included some server side universal JavaScript component to handle the initial page view. I’ve been working on learning more about the <a href="https://jamstack.org/">JAM Stack</a> which specifically does not include JavaScript running on the server. Seeing examples of this alternative stack helped get me thinking more about the pros and cons of both.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/component-based-drupal">Component Based Drupal</a> - Surprise! After a cancellation, <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/nerdstein">Adam Bergstein</a> and I stepped in without much of a safety net (I learned that I was co-presenting this session due to <a href="https://twitter.com/hook42inc/status/971837614004342784">a mention on twitter</a>) to talk about the current state of building and theming with components in Drupal. I’ve always enjoyed my conversations with Adam on this topic because while we primarily agree, we also have some differences of opinion and take some different approaches in our workflow. Continuing this conversation out in the open seemed to be useful to people, and I even got to joke around a little bit. I wouldn’t be surprised if Adam and I presented in a similar format in the future.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IUAVgejng9w" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Saturday - less traffic, more sessions.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/oop-pokemon-journey">OOP - The Pokemon Journey</a> / <a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/bending-behats-benefits-live-coding-adventure">Bending Behat's Benefits: A live coding adventure</a> - A journey followed by an adventure? Hell of a way to spend a groggy Saturday morning. I love hearing from both <a href="
">Fatima</a> and <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/stevector">Steve</a> whenever I can.  The OOP Pokemon Journey was a fun and easy to understand talk on a topic that I honestly don’t yet consider myself an expert on. And Bending Behat’s Benefits made me anxious to incorporate some more test driven development into my process after some time away.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/too-many-cooks-supporting-augmented-teams-without-getting-salty">Too many cooks! Supporting augmented teams without getting salty</a> - I wasn’t able to attend in person, but heard great things. It’s next up in the YouTube queue.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/american-medical-association-topic-landing-pages-d8-case-study">American Medical Association: Topic Landing Pages (A D8 Case Study)</a> - an excellent, and extremely relatable talk about the challenges of Drupal 8 landing page building integrated with a pattern library based approach to theming. I’ve felt so much similar pain/joy on recent projects. They also closed with the reminder that we all need to look into how Layout Builder in 8.5 and the Layout Initiative will impact this process going forward, which I think is extremely important.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/hot-jamstack-lessons-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">Hot JAMS(tack): Lessons from Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React</a> -This is my attempt to demystify the process of creating a decoupled app with Drupal and React by way of a fun side project. It was my first time giving a talk that I’ve had brewing for a while, and I was happy with how it went. Heard a lot of positive and helpful feedback and have a few things that I think I can tweak to make it more useful for people. Looking forward to presenting it again <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">at DrupalCon Nashville</a>.</p>

<p>Plus, this was pretty cool:
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Funny slide! <a href="https://t.co/LLqwuVXFb3">https://t.co/LLqwuVXFb3</a></p>&mdash; Dries Buytaert (@Dries) <a href="https://twitter.com/Dries/status/972816373545127936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 11, 2018</a></blockquote>
</p>

<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sj_nE2IukOs" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Sunday was sprints, and unfortunately more traffic on the way home.  I was dragging a little bit at this point, but still feel like I was able to get a few things done. I got back to the <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/foundation_patterns">Foundation Patterns</a> theme and responded to the first issue submitted against the project. I helped <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/amklose">Tony Klose</a> set up a Pattern Lab instance for a Drupal theme, and realized that I don’t have a clear personal process for including a pattern library as an external dependency of a theme. I also collaborated with Adam Bergstein a bit more looking at a possible React front-end for <a href="https://simplytest.me/">simplytest.me</a></p>

<p>
<ul>
Major Takeaways:
<li>I’d like to experiment more with Lando for local dev.</li>
<li>I want to understand more about the advantages and disadvantages between a decoupled architecture using universal JavaScript vs a JAM Stack approach.</li>
<li>I need to make time to better understand how the ongoing efforts related to the Layout Initiative will impact my component driven process.</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>A huge thanks goes out to the MidCamp organizers who overcame some pretty steep challenges to put on another great camp. I’ll see everyone next year at <a href="https://twitter.com/midwestcamp/status/973622480853225473">O’Midcamp</a>!</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/midcamp-2018-thoughts/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/midcamp-2018-thoughts/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Another year, another great MidCamp!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t able to attend for training and sprints on Thursday (1st grade play FTW!) but ended up talking to a former co-worker who attended the training &apos;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/training/what-am-i-getting-myself-drupal-crash-course-non-developers&quot;&gt;What Am I Getting Myself Into? A Drupal Crash Course for Non-Developers.&lt;/a&gt;’ While it&apos;s easy to get wrapped up in the new and advanced at a camp like this, it is also really important to see newcomers, beginners, and people with Drupal-adjacent roles take steps into becoming more hands on with the CMS. She specifically mentioned that the training helped her have some revelations about a few Drupal-isms that us crazy developers have been talking about all this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some really enjoyable traffic, Friday brought me to the first day of sessions.  A couple of highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/local-dev-environments-dummies&quot;&gt;Local Dev Environments for Dummies&lt;/a&gt; - the bulk of this presentation reviewed data from a 2018 Drupal Developer Survey, and the data alone was extremely fascinating. It also provided some interesting perspectives on Vagrant vs. Docker for local development (go Vagrant if matching your prod environment exactly is important, and Docker for pretty much everything else.) I also walked out of this one itching to learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.devwithlando.io/&quot;&gt;Lando&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/decoupled-drupal-across-stack&quot;&gt;Decoupled Drupal Across The Stack&lt;/a&gt; - always enjoy seeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/prestonso&quot;&gt;Preston&lt;/a&gt; speak about Decoupled Drupal, and being aware of his (and Acquia’s) perspective on the topic is important if I’m going to be speaking about adjacent topics as well. A good talk for  someone looking to survey the current Decoupled Drupal landscape. Was interesting to see that all of the examples Preston provided included some server side universal JavaScript component to handle the initial page view. I’ve been working on learning more about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamstack.org/&quot;&gt;JAM Stack&lt;/a&gt; which specifically does not include JavaScript running on the server. Seeing examples of this alternative stack helped get me thinking more about the pros and cons of both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/component-based-drupal&quot;&gt;Component Based Drupal&lt;/a&gt; - Surprise! After a cancellation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/nerdstein&quot;&gt;Adam Bergstein&lt;/a&gt; and I stepped in without much of a safety net (I learned that I was co-presenting this session due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hook42inc/status/971837614004342784&quot;&gt;a mention on twitter&lt;/a&gt;) to talk about the current state of building and theming with components in Drupal. I’ve always enjoyed my conversations with Adam on this topic because while we primarily agree, we also have some differences of opinion and take some different approaches in our workflow. Continuing this conversation out in the open seemed to be useful to people, and I even got to joke around a little bit. I wouldn’t be surprised if Adam and I presented in a similar format in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IUAVgejng9w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday - less traffic, more sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/oop-pokemon-journey&quot;&gt;OOP - The Pokemon Journey&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/bending-behats-benefits-live-coding-adventure&quot;&gt;Bending Behat&apos;s Benefits: A live coding adventure&lt;/a&gt; - A journey followed by an adventure? Hell of a way to spend a groggy Saturday morning. I love hearing from both &lt;a href=&quot;
&quot;&gt;Fatima&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/stevector&quot;&gt;Steve&lt;/a&gt; whenever I can.  The OOP Pokemon Journey was a fun and easy to understand talk on a topic that I honestly don’t yet consider myself an expert on. And Bending Behat’s Benefits made me anxious to incorporate some more test driven development into my process after some time away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/too-many-cooks-supporting-augmented-teams-without-getting-salty&quot;&gt;Too many cooks! Supporting augmented teams without getting salty&lt;/a&gt; - I wasn’t able to attend in person, but heard great things. It’s next up in the YouTube queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/american-medical-association-topic-landing-pages-d8-case-study&quot;&gt;American Medical Association: Topic Landing Pages (A D8 Case Study)&lt;/a&gt; - an excellent, and extremely relatable talk about the challenges of Drupal 8 landing page building integrated with a pattern library based approach to theming. I’ve felt so much similar pain/joy on recent projects. They also closed with the reminder that we all need to look into how Layout Builder in 8.5 and the Layout Initiative will impact this process going forward, which I think is extremely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/hot-jamstack-lessons-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;Hot JAMS(tack): Lessons from Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React&lt;/a&gt; -This is my attempt to demystify the process of creating a decoupled app with Drupal and React by way of a fun side project. It was my first time giving a talk that I’ve had brewing for a while, and I was happy with how it went. Heard a lot of positive and helpful feedback and have a few things that I think I can tweak to make it more useful for people. Looking forward to presenting it again &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;at DrupalCon Nashville&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, this was pretty cool:
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Funny slide! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/LLqwuVXFb3&quot;&gt;https://t.co/LLqwuVXFb3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dries Buytaert (@Dries) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Dries/status/972816373545127936?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 11, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sj_nE2IukOs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday was sprints, and unfortunately more traffic on the way home.  I was dragging a little bit at this point, but still feel like I was able to get a few things done. I got back to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/foundation_patterns&quot;&gt;Foundation Patterns&lt;/a&gt; theme and responded to the first issue submitted against the project. I helped &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/amklose&quot;&gt;Tony Klose&lt;/a&gt; set up a Pattern Lab instance for a Drupal theme, and realized that I don’t have a clear personal process for including a pattern library as an external dependency of a theme. I also collaborated with Adam Bergstein a bit more looking at a possible React front-end for &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplytest.me/&quot;&gt;simplytest.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
Major Takeaways:
&lt;li&gt;I’d like to experiment more with Lando for local dev.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to understand more about the advantages and disadvantages between a decoupled architecture using universal JavaScript vs a JAM Stack approach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to make time to better understand how the ongoing efforts related to the Layout Initiative will impact my component driven process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge thanks goes out to the MidCamp organizers who overcame some pretty steep challenges to put on another great camp. I’ll see everyone next year at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/midwestcamp/status/973622480853225473&quot;&gt;O’Midcamp&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here's how React's New Context API Works - Wes Bos]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Have been hedging my bets about learning Redux, but was getting close to taking the plunge. Now I'm wondering if React's upcoming Context API can meet my needs. Looking forward to more takes on advantages and disadvantages of the context API in comparison to things like Redux.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/here&apos;s-how-react&apos;s-new-context-api-works-wes-bos/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/here&apos;s-how-react&apos;s-new-context-api-works-wes-bos/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Have been hedging my bets about learning Redux, but was getting close to taking the plunge. Now I&apos;m wondering if React&apos;s upcoming Context API can meet my needs. Looking forward to more takes on advantages and disadvantages of the context API in comparison to things like Redux.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Accommodating Drupal In Your Components]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
While Drupalers are rejoicing at these exciting advances allowing newfound front end freedoms, there are still a few hoops to be aware of in order to make the most of Drupal, especially for a newcomer who might be eager to shove aside a lot of what Drupal provides. ...things that are easily dismissed in a component-driven approach, like letting Drupal fully render fields, can cause headaches further on if they’re ignored, and make life difficult when it comes to keeping your front end forward-compatible with Drupal.
</blockquote>

<p>The UI Patterns module really does solve many of the problems outlined in this post, so my preference is to embrace that approach and leave these complicated presenter templates behind. But for those who haven’t embraced <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns">UI Patterns</a>, this post really is essential.</p>

<p>When explaining some of the gotchas with this approach, I often use images as a simple example. Creating a component from scratch the instinct is often to pass in src and alt values as variables to get the cleanest markup possible. You can get that stuff out of Drupal, but it really is a pain. You’re better off just using the image markup Drupal renders, even if it isn't exactly as clean as you want it to be. Sometimes not fighting this battle at all is the right way to go. But if you want the perfect markup this post has everything you need to do it the right way.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/accommodating-drupal-in-your-components/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/accommodating-drupal-in-your-components/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
While Drupalers are rejoicing at these exciting advances allowing newfound front end freedoms, there are still a few hoops to be aware of in order to make the most of Drupal, especially for a newcomer who might be eager to shove aside a lot of what Drupal provides. ...things that are easily dismissed in a component-driven approach, like letting Drupal fully render fields, can cause headaches further on if they’re ignored, and make life difficult when it comes to keeping your front end forward-compatible with Drupal.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UI Patterns module really does solve many of the problems outlined in this post, so my preference is to embrace that approach and leave these complicated presenter templates behind. But for those who haven’t embraced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns&quot;&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;, this post really is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When explaining some of the gotchas with this approach, I often use images as a simple example. Creating a component from scratch the instinct is often to pass in src and alt values as variables to get the cleanest markup possible. You can get that stuff out of Drupal, but it really is a pain. You’re better off just using the image markup Drupal renders, even if it isn&apos;t exactly as clean as you want it to be. Sometimes not fighting this battle at all is the right way to go. But if you want the perfect markup this post has everything you need to do it the right way.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[CSS Tricks Rabbit Hole]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Went down a bit of a CSS-Tricks rabbit hole over lunch today.</p>

<p>Started with <a href="https://css-tricks.com/complexity/">Complexity.</a> I've enjoyed all of the recent point / counterpoints about the increasing complexity of front end development. This is a nice summary.</p>

<p>That led me to <a href="https://css-tricks.com/future-front-end-web-development/">The Future of Front End Web Development</a>. Totally agree with everything in there, maybe with the exception of 'the line between native and web is blurring.' I'd probably just put that one in the future-future of front end web development category. Not quite there yet, but looking forward to when it is more of a reality.</p>

<p>And then that led me to <a href="https://css-tricks.com/project-need-react/">When Does a Project Need React.</a> The more comfortable I become with how state is managed in a framework like React, the more insane our old jQuery tricks to jam state into the DOM seem.  That said, not all projects have complex state.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/css-tricks-rabbit-hole/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/css-tricks-rabbit-hole/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Went down a bit of a CSS-Tricks rabbit hole over lunch today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started with &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/complexity/&quot;&gt;Complexity.&lt;/a&gt; I&apos;ve enjoyed all of the recent point / counterpoints about the increasing complexity of front end development. This is a nice summary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That led me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/future-front-end-web-development/&quot;&gt;The Future of Front End Web Development&lt;/a&gt;. Totally agree with everything in there, maybe with the exception of &apos;the line between native and web is blurring.&apos; I&apos;d probably just put that one in the future-future of front end web development category. Not quite there yet, but looking forward to when it is more of a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then that led me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/project-need-react/&quot;&gt;When Does a Project Need React.&lt;/a&gt; The more comfortable I become with how state is managed in a framework like React, the more insane our old jQuery tricks to jam state into the DOM seem.  That said, not all projects have complex state.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[R U Talkin' R.E.M. RE: ME?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It's very hard to explain why, but I consider '<a href="http://www.earwolf.com/show/u-talkin-u2-to-me/">U Talkin' U2 2 Me?</a>' to be the greatest podcast of all time. Possibly just one of my favorite <em>things</em> of all time. I don't like U2 all that much, yet somehow hearing Scott and Scott break down U2's entire discography over 24 episodes was something I saved for special occasions and often laughed to the point of tears while listening to. And boy, did they ever spend a lot of time talking about the band U2 (not really.)  They even knew the names of every single member of the band. Truly encyclopedic knowledge.</p>

<p>And now Scott and Scott are back with '<a href="http://www.earwolf.com/show/u-talkin-u2-to-me/">R U Talkin' R.E.M. RE: ME?</a>' in which they explore the output of the band R.E.M in what I'm sure will be painstaking detail. I like R.E.M. more than I like U2, but I can't say I would ever want to go through their entire back catalog. Yet somehow here we are again, and I'm excited to hear all about the album Monster. Listening today was just like old times. Can't wait to save for long road trips and laugh to the point of nearly driving off the road.</p>

 <p>If you're looking for more info on what the hell this is all about, this <a href="https://www.stereogum.com/1981761/talkin-to-scott-aukerman-re-u-talkin-r-e-m-re-me/franchises/interview/">Stereogum interview</a> is as good a place as any. It might just confuse you more, which is par for the course.</p>

<p>Good ep.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/r-u-talkin&apos;-r.e.m.-re:-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/r-u-talkin&apos;-r.e.m.-re:-me/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s very hard to explain why, but I consider &apos;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.earwolf.com/show/u-talkin-u2-to-me/&quot;&gt;U Talkin&apos; U2 2 Me?&lt;/a&gt;&apos; to be the greatest podcast of all time. Possibly just one of my favorite &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; of all time. I don&apos;t like U2 all that much, yet somehow hearing Scott and Scott break down U2&apos;s entire discography over 24 episodes was something I saved for special occasions and often laughed to the point of tears while listening to. And boy, did they ever spend a lot of time talking about the band U2 (not really.)  They even knew the names of every single member of the band. Truly encyclopedic knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now Scott and Scott are back with &apos;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.earwolf.com/show/u-talkin-u2-to-me/&quot;&gt;R U Talkin&apos; R.E.M. RE: ME?&lt;/a&gt;&apos; in which they explore the output of the band R.E.M in what I&apos;m sure will be painstaking detail. I like R.E.M. more than I like U2, but I can&apos;t say I would ever want to go through their entire back catalog. Yet somehow here we are again, and I&apos;m excited to hear all about the album Monster. Listening today was just like old times. Can&apos;t wait to save for long road trips and laugh to the point of nearly driving off the road.&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re looking for more info on what the hell this is all about, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stereogum.com/1981761/talkin-to-scott-aukerman-re-u-talkin-r-e-m-re-me/franchises/interview/&quot;&gt;Stereogum interview&lt;/a&gt; is as good a place as any. It might just confuse you more, which is par for the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good ep.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Decoupled Drupal Dumb Problems: Malformed Markup]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/e0ipso">Mateu</a> has many of the Decoupled Drupal <a href="https://www.lullabot.com/articles/decoupled-drupal-hard-problems-image-styles">Hard</a> <a href="https://www.lullabot.com/articles/decoupled-hard-promblems-routing">Problems</a> well covered, so I'll take care of one of the dumb ones.</p>

<p>I noticed last weekend that the build was broken for this site - post switching on the homepage wasn't working, and as you scrolled down, posts started to be wrapped in the container for the previous post. I tried a new Gatsby build and saw the same thing. Next, I zeroed in on the post where content started overlapping and eventually noticed that I had some malformed markup in my post in Drupal - a missing closing quote for a href attribute. After updating the post to add the missing quote and doing another build, everything was fine again.</p>

<p>You could chalk most of this up to me - if I was using a wysiwyg editor it would have added the correct link markup for me, and I should probably be taking a closer look at my build after it goes to GitHub Pages. But I think this hiccup was a nice reminder of the reality of these super sexy decoupled architectures. We lose a bit of the protection that Drupal provided us from something like malformed markup in a body field making a page explode.  Builds will break in ways that they didn't with Drupal alone - the site worked fine in development mode but broke when the production bundle was built. And while testing is always important, we likely need to test in ways that are different from when we were testing Drupal by itself.</p>

<p>There are lessons to be learned even in the dumbest of problems. I'm sure I'll run into some more.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/decoupled-drupal-dumb-problems:-malformed-markup/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/decoupled-drupal-dumb-problems:-malformed-markup/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/e0ipso&quot;&gt;Mateu&lt;/a&gt; has many of the Decoupled Drupal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lullabot.com/articles/decoupled-drupal-hard-problems-image-styles&quot;&gt;Hard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lullabot.com/articles/decoupled-hard-promblems-routing&quot;&gt;Problems&lt;/a&gt; well covered, so I&apos;ll take care of one of the dumb ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed last weekend that the build was broken for this site - post switching on the homepage wasn&apos;t working, and as you scrolled down, posts started to be wrapped in the container for the previous post. I tried a new Gatsby build and saw the same thing. Next, I zeroed in on the post where content started overlapping and eventually noticed that I had some malformed markup in my post in Drupal - a missing closing quote for a href attribute. After updating the post to add the missing quote and doing another build, everything was fine again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could chalk most of this up to me - if I was using a wysiwyg editor it would have added the correct link markup for me, and I should probably be taking a closer look at my build after it goes to GitHub Pages. But I think this hiccup was a nice reminder of the reality of these super sexy decoupled architectures. We lose a bit of the protection that Drupal provided us from something like malformed markup in a body field making a page explode.  Builds will break in ways that they didn&apos;t with Drupal alone - the site worked fine in development mode but broke when the production bundle was built. And while testing is always important, we likely need to test in ways that are different from when we were testing Drupal by itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lessons to be learned even in the dumbest of problems. I&apos;m sure I&apos;ll run into some more.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[jQuery and Drupal 8.4 Upgrades]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Learned the hard way recently that Drupal 8.4 upgrades jQuery to jQuery 3.  This kills a few methods that were deprecated in previous versions of jQuery including .load(), .unload(), .error(), and .size().  The <a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/drupal/releases/8.4.0">release notes</a> cover this, but it didn't fully click until I actually ran into the issue.</p>
<p>Related: is a minor release really a minor release if it contains major release upgrades for a couple of your largest dependencies?</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/jquery-and-drupal-8.4-upgrades/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/jquery-and-drupal-8.4-upgrades/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Learned the hard way recently that Drupal 8.4 upgrades jQuery to jQuery 3.  This kills a few methods that were deprecated in previous versions of jQuery including .load(), .unload(), .error(), and .size().  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/project/drupal/releases/8.4.0&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; cover this, but it didn&apos;t fully click until I actually ran into the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related: is a minor release really a minor release if it contains major release upgrades for a couple of your largest dependencies?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[No More Guns Please]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Theresa Nicholls was eager to get back home as she packed her bags at the Hyatt Regency Chicago on Friday.</p>
<p>Her weeklong conference of school psychologists had been rocked by the mass shooting at a Florida high school. A day earlier, a Chicago police officer had been shot and killed in the Loop, just blocks from where she and her colleagues were staying.</p>
<p>As she was getting ready to check out, a friend texted her: There had just been a shooting in the lobby of her hotel.</p>
<p>“What the hell is going on?" she thought. "What is happening? It’s like the world is falling apart around us.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My wife was at this conference. There are a lot of reasons we need to do something about America's access to guns.  Let's add this one to the list.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/no-more-guns-please/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/no-more-guns-please/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theresa Nicholls was eager to get back home as she packed her bags at the Hyatt Regency Chicago on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her weeklong conference of school psychologists had been rocked by the mass shooting at a Florida high school. A day earlier, a Chicago police officer had been shot and killed in the Loop, just blocks from where she and her colleagues were staying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she was getting ready to check out, a friend texted her: There had just been a shooting in the lobby of her hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What the hell is going on?&quot; she thought. &quot;What is happening? It’s like the world is falling apart around us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife was at this conference. There are a lot of reasons we need to do something about America&apos;s access to guns.  Let&apos;s add this one to the list.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[React For Drupal]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A great collection of resources on creating decoupled applications with Drupal and React from the Lullabot folks.  Hope to contribute a link or two at some point.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/react-for-drupal/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/react-for-drupal/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A great collection of resources on creating decoupled applications with Drupal and React from the Lullabot folks.  Hope to contribute a link or two at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle End Developer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I say that I'm a 'full stack' developer, even though it is a term I've never really liked all that much.  The main reason that I don't like the term is because I feel like it doesn't mean that much to people. 
 Full stack developer kind of feels like someone saying 'I'll do whatever'.</p>

<p>I'm not sure if it is directly related to being a full stack developer, but over the years I've seen a pattern in how I'm utilized. In my various roles as a developer, I often start out doing front end work, and then over time find myself doing predominantly back end work. This could be because back end work has a higher value at the places I've worked.  It also could be because I suck at front end and just don't know it (hopefully not that one.) It's almost as if what people take full stack to mean is that the developer is exaggerating about their skill level on either the front or back end of the stack. Or maybe that they just haven't figured out which end of the stack their real talent lies.</p>

<p>I've always considered myself someone who prefers front end, so that is a bit of a challenging pattern to be stuck in. But lately I've been wondering, am I not being honest with myself?</p>

<p>Maybe I'm just describing myself wrong. I often describe myself as is a full stack developer with a preference for front end.  While that sounds kind of like a line from a personal ad, it does describe what I like to work on. I prefer front end work, can do back end work, and especially enjoy back end work  when it is in service of making front end work possible or better.</p>

<p>Drilling down on that last part brings us to the section where perhaps I'm not being honest with myself.</p>

<blockquote>I can do back end work, and especially enjoy it when it is in service of making front end work possible or better.</blockquote>

<p>Maybe my real thing is what lies in the middle.  The overlapping part of the venn diagram between front end and back end. </p>

<p>There is so much in the middle.</p>

<p>Helping front and back end developers communicate. Developing and maintaining pattern libraries. Helping different developers or different systems integrate with pattern libraries. Everything that goes with decoupled architectures - the APIs supporting them, the fancy JavaScript frameworks that use those APIs. And of course, stepping out of the middle when the situation calls for it.</p>

<p>Maybe I've been a middle end developer all along.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/middle-end-developer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/middle-end-developer/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I say that I&apos;m a &apos;full stack&apos; developer, even though it is a term I&apos;ve never really liked all that much.  The main reason that I don&apos;t like the term is because I feel like it doesn&apos;t mean that much to people. 
 Full stack developer kind of feels like someone saying &apos;I&apos;ll do whatever&apos;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not sure if it is directly related to being a full stack developer, but over the years I&apos;ve seen a pattern in how I&apos;m utilized. In my various roles as a developer, I often start out doing front end work, and then over time find myself doing predominantly back end work. This could be because back end work has a higher value at the places I&apos;ve worked.  It also could be because I suck at front end and just don&apos;t know it (hopefully not that one.) It&apos;s almost as if what people take full stack to mean is that the developer is exaggerating about their skill level on either the front or back end of the stack. Or maybe that they just haven&apos;t figured out which end of the stack their real talent lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve always considered myself someone who prefers front end, so that is a bit of a challenging pattern to be stuck in. But lately I&apos;ve been wondering, am I not being honest with myself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&apos;m just describing myself wrong. I often describe myself as is a full stack developer with a preference for front end.  While that sounds kind of like a line from a personal ad, it does describe what I like to work on. I prefer front end work, can do back end work, and especially enjoy back end work  when it is in service of making front end work possible or better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drilling down on that last part brings us to the section where perhaps I&apos;m not being honest with myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I can do back end work, and especially enjoy it when it is in service of making front end work possible or better.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe my real thing is what lies in the middle.  The overlapping part of the venn diagram between front end and back end. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping front and back end developers communicate. Developing and maintaining pattern libraries. Helping different developers or different systems integrate with pattern libraries. Everything that goes with decoupled architectures - the APIs supporting them, the fancy JavaScript frameworks that use those APIs. And of course, stepping out of the middle when the situation calls for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&apos;ve been a middle end developer all along.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[iO West Is Shutting Down Next Week - Splitsider]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<a href="https://www.io-west.com/">iO West</a>, the Los Angeles branch of Chicago’s iO Theater (formerly ImprovOlympic) founded by Del Close and Charna Halpern, is closing its doors for good next week.
</blockquote>

<p>At first it struck me as odd that many of my comedy friends on social media were talking about this like someone close to them had passed away, but I eventually realized that I've just been out of the comedy scene too long. If this happened to my home theater back in the <a href="http://improvboston.com">ImprovBoston</a> days, I probably would have reacted the exact same way. Running a theater is an inherently risky business and 25 years is quite an accomplishment. I hope everyone finds a new home to keep doing what they love.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/io-west-is-shutting-down-next-week-splitsider/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/io-west-is-shutting-down-next-week-splitsider/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.io-west.com/&quot;&gt;iO West&lt;/a&gt;, the Los Angeles branch of Chicago’s iO Theater (formerly ImprovOlympic) founded by Del Close and Charna Halpern, is closing its doors for good next week.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first it struck me as odd that many of my comedy friends on social media were talking about this like someone close to them had passed away, but I eventually realized that I&apos;ve just been out of the comedy scene too long. If this happened to my home theater back in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://improvboston.com&quot;&gt;ImprovBoston&lt;/a&gt; days, I probably would have reacted the exact same way. Running a theater is an inherently risky business and 25 years is quite an accomplishment. I hope everyone finds a new home to keep doing what they love.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[DrupalEasy Podcast 205 - Fatima Khalid - First time sprinter's guide]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
Fatima Khalid (<a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/sugaroverflow">sugaroverflow</a>), web developer with <a href="https://www.echidna.ca/">Digital Echidna</a>, and DrupalCon Nashville track chair and sprint mentor joins Mike Anello to talk about how to be a first-time sprinter at a local Drupal event or a DrupalCon and how she came for the community and stayed for the code.
</blockquote>

<p>Thought this was a really fun and accessible overview of what a sprint is like. I found them very intimidating at first and I think hearing an overview like this in advance would have helped.  Don't know how many first time sprinters are avid listeners of Drupal podcasts, but any little bit helps.<p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/drupaleasy-podcast-205-fatima-khalid-first-time-sprinter&apos;s-guide/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/drupaleasy-podcast-205-fatima-khalid-first-time-sprinter&apos;s-guide/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
Fatima Khalid (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/sugaroverflow&quot;&gt;sugaroverflow&lt;/a&gt;), web developer with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.echidna.ca/&quot;&gt;Digital Echidna&lt;/a&gt;, and DrupalCon Nashville track chair and sprint mentor joins Mike Anello to talk about how to be a first-time sprinter at a local Drupal event or a DrupalCon and how she came for the community and stayed for the code.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought this was a really fun and accessible overview of what a sprint is like. I found them very intimidating at first and I think hearing an overview like this in advance would have helped.  Don&apos;t know how many first time sprinters are avid listeners of Drupal podcasts, but any little bit helps.&lt;p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Designer-Oriented Styles - James Kyle]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>Each of these have trees of components which are made up of other components and elements (often named different things). Each element in the tree is independently styled. It's not built around cascading styles and the expectation is that you can copy any element and place it anywhere else and it will look identical.</blockquote>
<p>Interesting way to think about this - the end result of CSS-in-JS might just be what our designers wanted all along.</p>
<blockquote>Note: I’m going refer to “CSS-in-JS” as “Component-Oriented Styles” from here on out, because JavaScript really doesn’t have much to do with it. “CSS” will refer to the traditional way of writing .css files with selectors and all.</blockquote>
<p>I also really like the term "Component-Oriented Styles." Be it a methodology like <a href="http://getbem.com/">BEM</a> or a library like <a href="https://www.styled-components.com/">Styled Components</a>, we're really just trying to make styles predictable within the scope of of a reusable component.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/designer-oriented-styles-james-kyle/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/designer-oriented-styles-james-kyle/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;Each of these have trees of components which are made up of other components and elements (often named different things). Each element in the tree is independently styled. It&apos;s not built around cascading styles and the expectation is that you can copy any element and place it anywhere else and it will look identical.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting way to think about this - the end result of CSS-in-JS might just be what our designers wanted all along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Note: I’m going refer to “CSS-in-JS” as “Component-Oriented Styles” from here on out, because JavaScript really doesn’t have much to do with it. “CSS” will refer to the traditional way of writing .css files with selectors and all.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also really like the term &quot;Component-Oriented Styles.&quot; Be it a methodology like &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbem.com/&quot;&gt;BEM&lt;/a&gt; or a library like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.styled-components.com/&quot;&gt;Styled Components&lt;/a&gt;, we&apos;re really just trying to make styles predictable within the scope of of a reusable component.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[To PESOS or to POSSE - Dries Buytaert]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The <a href="https://indieweb.org">IndieWeb movement</a> has provided two clever names for these models:
</p>
<ol>
 <li><strong>PESOS</strong> or <a href="https://indieweb.org/PESOS">Publish Elsewhere, Syndicate (to your) Own Site</a> is a model where publishing begins on third party services, such as Facebook, and then copies can be syndicated to your own site.</li>
<li><strong>POSSE</strong> or <a href="https://indieweb.org/POSSE">Publish (on your) Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere</a> is a publishing model that begins with posting content on your own site first, then syndicating out copies to third party services.</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
<p>I've been thinking about this as well as I build out this website. I fall into the POSSE camp, and right now it's completely manual and mostly just me posting links on Twitter. To some extent, I'm even fine with this website just being its own disconnected thing. It will always be a small subset of my social network that would make it here and actually read something, and that seems just about right.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/to-pesos-or-to-posse-dries-buytaert/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/to-pesos-or-to-posse-dries-buytaert/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org&quot;&gt;IndieWeb movement&lt;/a&gt; has provided two clever names for these models:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PESOS&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/PESOS&quot;&gt;Publish Elsewhere, Syndicate (to your) Own Site&lt;/a&gt; is a model where publishing begins on third party services, such as Facebook, and then copies can be syndicated to your own site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POSSE&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&quot;&gt;Publish (on your) Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; is a publishing model that begins with posting content on your own site first, then syndicating out copies to third party services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve been thinking about this as well as I build out this website. I fall into the POSSE camp, and right now it&apos;s completely manual and mostly just me posting links on Twitter. To some extent, I&apos;m even fine with this website just being its own disconnected thing. It will always be a small subset of my social network that would make it here and actually read something, and that seems just about right.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Source Drupal Filters by Published]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>When initially setting up <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-source-drupal/">gatsby-source-drupal</a> for this site I started thinking about how I could adjust my GraphQL query to only include published posts. I eventually realized that the plugin was already doing that by default. That isn't always the case for stuff like this, so it was a nice time saver.</p>

<p>I also found that <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-source-drupal/">gatsby-source-drupal</a> seems to work best with <a href="http://www.contentacms.org/">Contenta</a> for some reason.  More on that soon - I'm hoping to have a longer post on Drupal and Gatsby at some point.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/gatsby-source-drupal-filters-by-published/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/gatsby-source-drupal-filters-by-published/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When initially setting up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-source-drupal/&quot;&gt;gatsby-source-drupal&lt;/a&gt; for this site I started thinking about how I could adjust my GraphQL query to only include published posts. I eventually realized that the plugin was already doing that by default. That isn&apos;t always the case for stuff like this, so it was a nice time saver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-source-drupal/&quot;&gt;gatsby-source-drupal&lt;/a&gt; seems to work best with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.contentacms.org/&quot;&gt;Contenta&lt;/a&gt; for some reason.  More on that soon - I&apos;m hoping to have a longer post on Drupal and Gatsby at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[MidCamp Needs Your Help]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.midcamp.org/">MidCamp</a> is my home base Drupal camp and one that I've attended for years. This week the organizers apparently ran into a pretty major snag with some budgeting issues with the venue.</p>

<p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">So <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/midcamp?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#midcamp</a> just received some bad news from our venue. If you want to see this camp continue, please strongly consider sponsorship. We need all the help we can get right now: <a href="https://t.co/xBG0xx8DKz">https://t.co/xBG0xx8DKz</a></p>&mdash; Kevin Thull (@kevinjthull) <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinjthull/status/961675493199220736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 8, 2018</a></blockquote>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Clarification regarding <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/midcamp?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#midcamp</a> news: Since we just found out we won&#39;t qualify for our venue discount for this year, we are looking to raise an additional $15,000 in sponsorship before 2/15 before making drastic cuts.</p>&mdash; Kevin Thull (@kevinjthull) <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinjthull/status/961698243808825344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 8, 2018</a></blockquote></p>

<p>For me, MidCamp is a really important part of staying connected with the Chicago-area Drupal community.  It is also the first Drupal event I ever presented at, and <a href="https://www.midcamp.org/topic/hot-jamstack-lessons-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">I'm scheduled to speak again</a> this year. I'd really hate to see MidCamp have to scale back and not be the MidCamp we all know it can be.</p>

<p>There are many ways you can help. If you have a company (or a rich uncle) that could <a href="https://www.midcamp.org/become-a-sponsor">sponsor</a>, that could make a huge difference. If you have the means to <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/midcamp-2018-midwest-drupal-camp-chicago-illinois-tickets-41173372666#tickets">become an individual sponsor</a>, that would help too. Word is that they are also working on an option to accept smaller donations as well. And if none of that is possible, <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/midcamp-2018-midwest-drupal-camp-chicago-illinois-tickets-41173372666">registering</a> or <a href="https://www.midcamp.org/article/call-volunteers">volunteering</a> helps.</p>

<p>Do what you can, and hopefully we can all make it happen. Looking forward to seeing everyone in Chicago in March.</p>

<p>Update: MidCamp is also accepting donations of any size</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I really appreciate the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/drupal?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#drupal</a> community love and support for <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MidCamp?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MidCamp</a>. We can now accept donations via eventbrite: <a href="https://t.co/ng94RjAmnS">https://t.co/ng94RjAmnS</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/stayforthecommunity?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#stayforthecommunity</a></p>&mdash; Kevin Thull (@kevinjthull) <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinjthull/status/962031353469415425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 9, 2018</a></blockquote>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/midcamp-needs-your-help/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/midcamp-needs-your-help/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/&quot;&gt;MidCamp&lt;/a&gt; is my home base Drupal camp and one that I&apos;ve attended for years. This week the organizers apparently ran into a pretty major snag with some budgeting issues with the venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;So &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/midcamp?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#midcamp&lt;/a&gt; just received some bad news from our venue. If you want to see this camp continue, please strongly consider sponsorship. We need all the help we can get right now: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/xBG0xx8DKz&quot;&gt;https://t.co/xBG0xx8DKz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kevin Thull (@kevinjthull) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinjthull/status/961675493199220736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 8, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Clarification regarding &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/midcamp?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#midcamp&lt;/a&gt; news: Since we just found out we won&amp;#39;t qualify for our venue discount for this year, we are looking to raise an additional $15,000 in sponsorship before 2/15 before making drastic cuts.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kevin Thull (@kevinjthull) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinjthull/status/961698243808825344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 8, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, MidCamp is a really important part of staying connected with the Chicago-area Drupal community.  It is also the first Drupal event I ever presented at, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/topic/hot-jamstack-lessons-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;I&apos;m scheduled to speak again&lt;/a&gt; this year. I&apos;d really hate to see MidCamp have to scale back and not be the MidCamp we all know it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways you can help. If you have a company (or a rich uncle) that could &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/become-a-sponsor&quot;&gt;sponsor&lt;/a&gt;, that could make a huge difference. If you have the means to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/midcamp-2018-midwest-drupal-camp-chicago-illinois-tickets-41173372666#tickets&quot;&gt;become an individual sponsor&lt;/a&gt;, that would help too. Word is that they are also working on an option to accept smaller donations as well. And if none of that is possible, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/midcamp-2018-midwest-drupal-camp-chicago-illinois-tickets-41173372666&quot;&gt;registering&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/article/call-volunteers&quot;&gt;volunteering&lt;/a&gt; helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what you can, and hopefully we can all make it happen. Looking forward to seeing everyone in Chicago in March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: MidCamp is also accepting donations of any size&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I really appreciate the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/drupal?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#drupal&lt;/a&gt; community love and support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/MidCamp?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#MidCamp&lt;/a&gt;. We can now accept donations via eventbrite: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ng94RjAmnS&quot;&gt;https://t.co/ng94RjAmnS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/stayforthecommunity?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#stayforthecommunity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Kevin Thull (@kevinjthull) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kevinjthull/status/962031353469415425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 9, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Celeste]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-video" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Really enjoying Celeste so far. <a href="https://t.co/YAHpq2XdhJ">pic.twitter.com/YAHpq2XdhJ</a></p>&mdash; Brian Perry (@bricomedy) <a href="https://twitter.com/bricomedy/status/957399535206060032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 27, 2018</a></blockquote>

<p>Can't recommend <a href="http://www.celestegame.com/">Celeste</a> enough. Perfect for Switch.</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/celeste/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/note/celeste/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-video&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Really enjoying Celeste so far. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/YAHpq2XdhJ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/YAHpq2XdhJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brian Perry (@bricomedy) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bricomedy/status/957399535206060032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 27, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&apos;t recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.celestegame.com/&quot;&gt;Celeste&lt;/a&gt; enough. Perfect for Switch.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[DrupalCon Nashville Session Proposals]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The call for <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018">DrupalCon Nashville</a> session proposals closed this past Wednesday and I was able to get my act together enough to submit two of them.  The process of putting together a session submission is always an interesting one for me. For DrupalCon it is usually a wonderful mix of overanalyzing, combined with good old fashioned imposter syndrome. That said, I feel like I improve each time around, and I think these are my strongest proposals yet.</p>

<p>Submission one was '<a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/component-based-theming-ui-patterns">Component Based Theming with UI Patterns</a>.' <a href="https://nedcamp.org/new-england-drupal-camp/sessions/component-based-theming-ui-patterns">I've given this talk before</a> and was happy with how it turned out. I submitted this one very early, and also noticed that <a href="https://www.drupal.org/u/mariohernandez">Mario Hernandez</a> had submitted <a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/integrating-components-uipatterns">another talk on the topic as well</a>. In hindsight, I should have reached out to him and seen if there was any way to collaborate as he ended up joining up with another speaker for his session. Lesson learned for next time.</p>

<p>Submission two was '<a href="https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-lessons-learned-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react">Hot JAMS(tack): Lessons from Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React</a>.' Strong competition as well here with many Decoupled Drupal and React related topics, but Im hoping I have a slightly different angle that might garner some interest. True to my usual form, I also went with a goofy, high-concept approach with the submission. Almost got cold feet about going in that direction, but decided I'd rather have fun with it. Ironically, with a proposal that heavily references music, I didn't even make the Music City connection until writing this post. Would have been fun to play that angle up more.</p>

<p>This will be my third time submitting sessions to DrupalCon North America (which I guess is now just DrupalCon?) I've never been selected, but I have been asked to be on call as a back up speaker, which I had no idea was even a thing. Regardless of the outcome, I enjoyed the process putting these session proposals together and look forward to Nashville this year. I've never been!</p>

<p>Update: Was a little wrapped up in the DrupalCon deadline, but I also submitted both of these sessions to <a href="https://www.midcamp.org/">MidCamp</a> in Chicago. In addition to being my home camp, MidCamp is always really, really great. You should go!</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/drupalcon-nashville-session-proposals/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/drupalcon-nashville-session-proposals/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The call for &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018&quot;&gt;DrupalCon Nashville&lt;/a&gt; session proposals closed this past Wednesday and I was able to get my act together enough to submit two of them.  The process of putting together a session submission is always an interesting one for me. For DrupalCon it is usually a wonderful mix of overanalyzing, combined with good old fashioned imposter syndrome. That said, I feel like I improve each time around, and I think these are my strongest proposals yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submission one was &apos;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/component-based-theming-ui-patterns&quot;&gt;Component Based Theming with UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;.&apos; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nedcamp.org/new-england-drupal-camp/sessions/component-based-theming-ui-patterns&quot;&gt;I&apos;ve given this talk before&lt;/a&gt; and was happy with how it turned out. I submitted this one very early, and also noticed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/u/mariohernandez&quot;&gt;Mario Hernandez&lt;/a&gt; had submitted &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/integrating-components-uipatterns&quot;&gt;another talk on the topic as well&lt;/a&gt;. In hindsight, I should have reached out to him and seen if there was any way to collaborate as he ended up joining up with another speaker for his session. Lesson learned for next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submission two was &apos;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.drupal.org/nashville2018/sessions/hot-jamstack-lessons-learned-building-music-discovery-app-drupal-and-react&quot;&gt;Hot JAMS(tack): Lessons from Building a Music Discovery App with Drupal and React&lt;/a&gt;.&apos; Strong competition as well here with many Decoupled Drupal and React related topics, but Im hoping I have a slightly different angle that might garner some interest. True to my usual form, I also went with a goofy, high-concept approach with the submission. Almost got cold feet about going in that direction, but decided I&apos;d rather have fun with it. Ironically, with a proposal that heavily references music, I didn&apos;t even make the Music City connection until writing this post. Would have been fun to play that angle up more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be my third time submitting sessions to DrupalCon North America (which I guess is now just DrupalCon?) I&apos;ve never been selected, but I have been asked to be on call as a back up speaker, which I had no idea was even a thing. Regardless of the outcome, I enjoyed the process putting these session proposals together and look forward to Nashville this year. I&apos;ve never been!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: Was a little wrapped up in the DrupalCon deadline, but I also submitted both of these sessions to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.midcamp.org/&quot;&gt;MidCamp&lt;/a&gt; in Chicago. In addition to being my home camp, MidCamp is always really, really great. You should go!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nintendo Labo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<blockquote>Today, the company revealed a new initiative dubbed Nintendo Labo, which involves DIY cardboard accessories that can transform the Switch’s Joy-Con controllers into everything from a fishing rod to a piano to a full-on robot suit. These accessories are then used to control a variety of mini-games, essentially turning the Switch tablet into a tiny arcade.</blockquote>
<p>Paraphrasing, but when I told my wife about Labo she said, "Nintendo is going to get you to buy a cardboard box, aren't they?"</p>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/nintendo-labo/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/link/nintendo-labo/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;Today, the company revealed a new initiative dubbed Nintendo Labo, which involves DIY cardboard accessories that can transform the Switch’s Joy-Con controllers into everything from a fishing rod to a piano to a full-on robot suit. These accessories are then used to control a variety of mini-games, essentially turning the Switch tablet into a tiny arcade.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paraphrasing, but when I told my wife about Labo she said, &quot;Nintendo is going to get you to buy a cardboard box, aren&apos;t they?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building Something from Nothing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div>
<p>It wouldn't be a new year without the desire to relaunch my personal website.  Happy 2018!</p>
<p>It could be another case of New Years delusion, but this year I think the timing might actually make sense. Over the past year I've been exploring <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a> and the world of <a href="https://dri.es/how-to-decouple-drupal-in-2018">Decoupled Drupal</a>. After working through <a href="http://wesbos.com/">Wes Bos</a>' <a href="https://reactforbeginners.com/">React For Beginners</a> course and having some concepts finally click, I took another shot at creating <a href="http://brianperryinteractive.com/aoty-visualizations/">a web app based on the Album of the Year Project</a>. Having a project I could slowly chip away at over the year provided a great low pressure way to learn, and also prevented me from having to re-learn things as they vanished from my brain. I'd love to duplicate that situation in 2018.</p>
<p>Next up learning wise I'm planning on continuing my experimentation with the <a href="https://jamstack.org/">JAMstack</a> by way of <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/">Gatsby.js</a>. I like what I've seen of Gatsby thus far. It allows me to leverage all of the things I've enjoyed about React, while combining that with the features of a static site generator like <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> or <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>. And it plays nice with <a href="https://www.drupal.org/8">Drupal 8</a> as well, which is a plus.</p>
<p>So welcome to my new Gatsby site. It will be nice to have an active personal website again, but perhaps even more exciting is the fact that this serves as another low pressure project I can chip away at throughout 2018 to learn more about React and decoupling Drupal. I'll start out with a site very close to nothing - little content, little styling - and slowly add new stuff as time and interest allows.</p>
<p>With any luck this site will look completely different by the time 2019 approaches. And hopefully I will have learned a thing or two along the way.  If you're curious, <a href="https://github.com/backlineint/brianperryinteractive">the code is available on GitHub</a>.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/building-something-from-nothing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://brianperryinteractive.com/post/building-something-from-nothing/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&apos;t be a new year without the desire to relaunch my personal website.  Happy 2018!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be another case of New Years delusion, but this year I think the timing might actually make sense. Over the past year I&apos;ve been exploring &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt; and the world of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dri.es/how-to-decouple-drupal-in-2018&quot;&gt;Decoupled Drupal&lt;/a&gt;. After working through &lt;a href=&quot;http://wesbos.com/&quot;&gt;Wes Bos&lt;/a&gt;&apos; &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactforbeginners.com/&quot;&gt;React For Beginners&lt;/a&gt; course and having some concepts finally click, I took another shot at creating &lt;a href=&quot;http://brianperryinteractive.com/aoty-visualizations/&quot;&gt;a web app based on the Album of the Year Project&lt;/a&gt;. Having a project I could slowly chip away at over the year provided a great low pressure way to learn, and also prevented me from having to re-learn things as they vanished from my brain. I&apos;d love to duplicate that situation in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up learning wise I&apos;m planning on continuing my experimentation with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamstack.org/&quot;&gt;JAMstack&lt;/a&gt; by way of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby.js&lt;/a&gt;. I like what I&apos;ve seen of Gatsby thus far. It allows me to leverage all of the things I&apos;ve enjoyed about React, while combining that with the features of a static site generator like &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;. And it plays nice with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drupal.org/8&quot;&gt;Drupal 8&lt;/a&gt; as well, which is a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So welcome to my new Gatsby site. It will be nice to have an active personal website again, but perhaps even more exciting is the fact that this serves as another low pressure project I can chip away at throughout 2018 to learn more about React and decoupling Drupal. I&apos;ll start out with a site very close to nothing - little content, little styling - and slowly add new stuff as time and interest allows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With any luck this site will look completely different by the time 2019 approaches. And hopefully I will have learned a thing or two along the way.  If you&apos;re curious, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/backlineint/brianperryinteractive&quot;&gt;the code is available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>